<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Open Libra Documentation Blog</title>
        <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog</link>
        <description>Open Libra Documentation Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open Libra: The Road Less Traveled]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/the-road-less-traveled</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/the-road-less-traveled</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A force of the public which has the capital necessary to make meaningful interventions, at the scale of the largest organizations in society. This requires independence, durability, and sense.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>A force of the public which has the capital necessary to make meaningful interventions, at the scale of the largest organizations in society. This requires independence, durability, and sense.</strong></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="independent-perpetual-sensible">Independent, Perpetual, Sensible<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/the-road-less-traveled#independent-perpetual-sensible" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Independent, Perpetual, Sensible" title="Direct link to Independent, Perpetual, Sensible">​</a></h3>
<p><em>OL looks different because it is different.</em> Open Libra does not have a foundation, has no labs entity, no VC funding, and no ICO. Why not? Because, unlike the First In - First Out pump and dump schemes that litter the Crypto landscape, Open Libra has a clean regulatory and moral profile to serve our focused mission — perpetual funding for impact in society, independent of corporations, governments, and traditional finance of the day.</p>
<p>The unique feature of digital assets is their opportunity to be perpetual, a highly misunderstood and underrated property. OL measures its plans in centuries, on much longer scales than you are accustomed to if you are in tech. But if instead the product is defined as independent and good capital, then a 100-year time frame is plausible. The next generations should expect there to exist an institution (more like a force of the public) which has the capital necessary to make meaningful interventions, at the scale of the largest organizations in society. Open Libra is five years in, and still pre-launch. Deliberately being principled, vigilant, and evolutionary.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="forget-cryptocurrency-think-open-titles">Forget Cryptocurrency, Think <em>Open Titles</em><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/the-road-less-traveled#forget-cryptocurrency-think-open-titles" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to forget-cryptocurrency-think-open-titles" title="Direct link to forget-cryptocurrency-think-open-titles">​</a></h3>
<p>The future lies in the thing that comes after currencies: durable capital which can accumulate entitlements, benefits, and rights over time. Digital titles that are both accessible and enforceable over generations, far beyond transient software versions and networks. Crypto makes a tacit promise: wealth while participating in what the future brings. We extend that further to create a product everyone would want to be a part of: to invite the 98% of the world who seek to participate in future themes of technology, social coordination, and build wealth through engagement with society.</p>
<p>We ask difficult questions of the industry because, to us, the design space is clear, but the offers in the market are not.</p>
<p>Learn more about our vision at <a href="https://openlibra.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://openlibra.io</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="2024-a-year-of-resilience-and-progress">2024: A Year of Resilience and Progress<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/the-road-less-traveled#2024-a-year-of-resilience-and-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 2024: A Year of Resilience and Progress" title="Direct link to 2024: A Year of Resilience and Progress">​</a></h2>
<p>2024 was a pivotal year for Open Libra. Reinforcing our commitment to the long game, the project undertook several strategic measures to solidify its foothold and secure the mission.</p>
<p>We faced an exploit, a multi-step governance abuse which involved social engineering, deception, and transaction manipulation.</p>
<p><strong>This was not a software failure, but a breach of trust.</strong></p>
<p>This of course, is not a surprise, and neither an unexpected disappointment. OL goes slow in order to observe and correct the course. The abuse unfolded faster precisely because the exploiters began to take notice of the core founding team that was catching up to the evidence.</p>
<p>The active community responded with an industry-leading forensic process that disabled 98% of exploited funds, demonstrating our commitment to fairness and justice in our community. The community has been clear from the beginning, that we do not invite or suffer that Open Libra is not for the 2% seeking quick wins at the expense of fellow community members. To address these challenges, a hard fork was executed and forensic tools were created, available at <a href="https://github.com/openlibra" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub</a>, facilitating interoperability and expanding the Open Libra ecosystem.</p>
<p>It took months to develop Forensic Db, a missing piece of blockchains. The comprehensive forensic database ensures project accountability and transparency. Where necessary, proper authorities in The Netherlands were also engaged to ensure regulatory compliance and proper legal standing.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="learnings">Learnings<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/the-road-less-traveled#learnings" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Learnings" title="Direct link to Learnings">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="socialized-enforcement">Socialized Enforcement<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/the-road-less-traveled#socialized-enforcement" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Socialized Enforcement" title="Direct link to Socialized Enforcement">​</a></h3>
<p>Unlike traditional blockchain projects with centralized governance structures, Open Libra enforces norms through four levels of socialized enforcement. When loose social consensus fails, you should expect to see several layers of enforcement:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Smart Contracts:</strong> Improve the binding of key policies of your community norms.</li>
<li><strong>Social Slashing:</strong> Start a new network that reinforces the norms, move the party elsewhere.</li>
<li><strong>Civil Legal Recourse:</strong> Utilizing judicial systems is fair game when Smart contracts are multi-party agreements.</li>
<li><strong>Criminal Enforcement:</strong> Ultimately, criminal enforcement is reasonable against fraud and misconduct when a sovereign's laws overlap with ours.</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="first-in-last-out-is-worth-fighting-for">First In Last Out is Worth Fighting For<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/the-road-less-traveled#first-in-last-out-is-worth-fighting-for" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to First In Last Out is Worth Fighting For" title="Direct link to First In Last Out is Worth Fighting For">​</a></h3>
<p>One of OL's oldest founding beliefs is that First In First Out leads to abuse in markets (pump and dump). Many of our exemplary policies (Slow Wallets, Community Wallets) are explicitly designed with a goal of “First In, Last Out” principle. In 2024, we diverged from this norm, both intentionally by exploiters and unintentionally by distraction. Governance upgrades have been proposed and are in progress to ground us in this principle again.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="looking-forward-to-2025-and-beyond">Looking Forward to 2025 and Beyond<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/the-road-less-traveled#looking-forward-to-2025-and-beyond" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Looking Forward to 2025 and Beyond" title="Direct link to Looking Forward to 2025 and Beyond">​</a></h2>
<p>As the project sets its sights on the future, Open Libra will introduce several key initiatives in 2025 designed to reinforce its mission and expand its impact:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>SlowWalletV2 Proposal:</strong> Enhancing security and longevity for long-term holders.</li>
<li><strong>Project Nest Egg:</strong> An initiative that aims to transform Libra into a force for good by funding high-quality real-world businesses by effectively deploying capital through Community Wallets. By harnessing voluntary contributions, these wallets become a strategic asset, driving sustainable growth and innovation within the ecosystem.</li>
<li><strong>Validator Bidding Optimization:</strong> Streamlining the validator selection process for greater efficiency.</li>
<li><strong>Exchange Listing Initiatives:</strong> Community-driven efforts to expand accessibility and liquidity.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="join-us">Join Us<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/the-road-less-traveled#join-us" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Join Us" title="Direct link to Join Us">​</a></h2>
<p><em>The active community invite experts across disciplines who align with our mission and are committed to sustainable, long-term impact to JOIN US: <a href="https://openlibra.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://openlibra.io</a>.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>blog</category>
            <category>news</category>
            <category>canonical</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Open Libra NodeJS Library Has Been Published on npm 🔥]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/openlibra-nodejs-release</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/openlibra-nodejs-release</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Congratulations to the Open Libra contributors!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Congratulations to the Open Libra contributors!</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="open-libra-nodejs-library-open-libra-sdk-has-been-published-on-the-npm-repository"><strong>Open Libra NodeJS library</strong> <code>open-libra-sdk</code> has been published on the npm repository!<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/openlibra-nodejs-release#open-libra-nodejs-library-open-libra-sdk-has-been-published-on-the-npm-repository" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to open-libra-nodejs-library-open-libra-sdk-has-been-published-on-the-npm-repository" title="Direct link to open-libra-nodejs-library-open-libra-sdk-has-been-published-on-the-npm-repository">​</a></h3>
<p>This SDK brings you an easy way to integrate Open Libra blockchain functionality into your NodeJS applications. Whether you’re building new decentralized apps or exploring blockchain integrations, this library provides the essential tools to get started.</p>
<p>For complete installation details, usage instructions, and further information, please visit the npm repository page:</p>
<p>👉 <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/open-libra-sdk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">npm package page for open-libra-sdk</a>.</p>
<p>Carpe Diem!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>open-libra-sdk</category>
            <category>npm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scorpion's Claw Recommendation]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Community Wallet Analytics and V7 Hard Fork Parameters [DRAFT]]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="community-wallet-analytics-and-v7-hard-fork-parameters-draft">Community Wallet Analytics and V7 Hard Fork Parameters [DRAFT]<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#community-wallet-analytics-and-v7-hard-fork-parameters-draft" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Community Wallet Analytics and V7 Hard Fork Parameters [DRAFT]" title="Direct link to Community Wallet Analytics and V7 Hard Fork Parameters [DRAFT]">​</a></h2>
<p>April 9th 2024</p>
<h1>TL;DR</h1>
<p>Operation Scorpion’s Claw identified 4.012 billion LIBRA involved in instances of abuse of the community wallet tooling; approximately 4% of the total supply.</p>
<p>A methodical approach was used to programmatically identify participating accounts. The endeavor took four weeks because</p>
<ul>
<li>new tools were developed</li>
<li>new technologies implemented</li>
<li>platform software updated</li>
</ul>
<p>The result is a list of 436 accounts. If validators decide, they can now run a version of a network aiming to exclude dishonest accounts. The dishonest accounts which currently contain 3,768,939,592 LIBRA.</p>
<p>There was a handful of abuse cases. However, the vast majority of the exploit was conducted by a long-term community member who has publicly declared ownership of the accounts originating the exploit.</p>
<ul>
<li><code>6DA2B828F3018637379203940C639A95</code></li>
<li><code>27E9577869ADFD677DBA9C940DEECE0A</code></li>
<li><code>988B8C3B7E55B6E5126884E02C8F166E</code></li>
</ul>
<p>A hard fork is recommended, and should happen with a validator ceremony open to the public and using a clean database using the version 7.0.0 software release.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXfpdWi_O_kHFqEKhvBDfr41QGlcBVH2As0u3xr5Hd0Fxb0IN9N8rBHfvFI5u76rOGSKZZFa36kWdY77XqVWhpRhSgptePszHNlvZJ-tptwfzZsp-WNkvVQLQyg4JTAe2N-uZDuTfhuO2I5XAuao1-1q84B1?key=UdkA8jBMllBve2WagZXXwA" alt="image" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h1>What Happened</h1>
<p>In preparation for the release of the 0L Network v7 Mainnet, analytics contributors ran a comprehensive on-chain analysis of all user-generated events – code named “Scorpion’s Claw”. This meticulous examination revealed several instances of abuse, predominantly to the Donor Voice accounts ("community wallets") which are a great source of pride of the 0L community.</p>
<p>Before a report on these abuses could be completed, the rogue players discovered the operation was underway and began to drain accounts into OTC markets. Some validators responded by stopping their nodes, preferring to wait for the final report and remediation recommendations than to continue participating on a network with that behavior. Many community members were interested in a Hard Fork. This report provides the facts, and basis for which a hard fork could be conducted.</p>
<p>Operation Scorpion’s Claw identified 4.012 billion LIBRA involved in these instances of abuse, or approximately 4% of the total supply.</p>
<p>In this report, a list of the accounts involved in the abuse has been developed by strictly adhering to the following goals:</p>
<ul>
<li>A deterministic approach for inclusion criteria.</li>
<li>Maximum removal of misappropriated supply.</li>
<li>Minimal adverse impact to uninvolved parties.</li>
</ul>
<p>This endeavor yielded a final list of 436 accounts, holding 3,768,939,592 LIBRA.</p>
<p>Scorpion's Claw proposes that on a new network, these accounts will be excluded by being rendered inaccessible. As such, the associated supply will be permanently removed from circulation. These actions signify an exclusion rate of the total amount of dishonestly appropriated coins of 94%.</p>
<p>As with any hard fork the prior software would remain available to those who wish to continue on the prior chain. Though the recommendation of this report is that such a chain would not be popular with users for social and economic reasons, users and validators remain free to use that version of the chain if they so choose.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="background">Background<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#background" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Background" title="Direct link to Background">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="design-philosophy">Design Philosophy<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#design-philosophy" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Design Philosophy" title="Direct link to Design Philosophy">​</a></h3>
<p>The 0LNetwork community champions self-correcting systems instead of rigid white list driven systems with authoritarian control. Many 0L designers are informed by Karl Popper's vision of an open society and naturally self-correcting systems. This open approach to design and operations, while prone to exploitation, is essential for progress and encourages boundary testing that allows policy to evolve naturally. Exploitation and innovation are often distinguishable only in retrospect so open systems are necessarily open to what will later prove to be fraud. Eliminate any opportunity for exploitation and one also eliminates any opportunity for evolution. Exploit and evolve. We regard the tradeoff with equanimity.</p>
<p>Blockchains are probabilistic, not deterministic, systems. Hard forks in this paradigm are viewed not as indicators of failure nor guarantees of success, but as strategic adjustments that are vital to the longevity and success of a robust network which is resistant to abuse and central control.</p>
<p>0L's Approach to open policies:</p>
<ul>
<li>Emphasize the absence of absolute guarantees, lean on probabilities.</li>
<li>Reject the need for foundational authority, embrace open participation.</li>
<li>Recognize the constructive role of exploits and boundary-pushing by participants.</li>
<li>Accept hard forks as evolutionary steps within the policy framework, aimed for continuous improvement.</li>
<li>Invite a dynamic interaction with policies, where challenges are opportunities for advancement.</li>
<li>Underscore the importance of adaptability and innovation in navigating open policies.</li>
</ul>
<p>In this paradigm hard forks are viewed not as indicators of failure (nor success) but as strategic adjustments that are vital to the longevity and success of a robust network.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="0l-network-policies">0L Network Policies<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#0l-network-policies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 0L Network Policies" title="Direct link to 0L Network Policies">​</a></h3>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="slow-wallets">Slow Wallets<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#slow-wallets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Slow Wallets" title="Direct link to Slow Wallets">​</a></h4>
<p>Ordinary wallets don’t limit transfer amounts and have no balance restrictions. Transactions are immediate in the typical wallet a user would initialize (e.g. in Carpe).</p>
<p>Early participants in a network may receive generous subsidies, but the chain’s policies should be designed in such a way as to prevent early participants from dumping on less sophisticated users. To address this need, rewards are sent to Slow Wallets (SW) rather than regular wallets. All validator node accounts, where a majority of rewards flow, are Slow Wallets. Slow Wallets have a drip mechanism that unlocks its balance in increments of 35k coins per epoch until the full balance eventually becomes unlocked.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="community-wallets">Community Wallets<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#community-wallets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Community Wallets" title="Direct link to Community Wallets">​</a></h4>
<p>0L Network chain provides tools and patterns for communities to self-fund their activities with LIBRA. One pattern is the Donor Voice participatory payments together with Matching Donation Index, a.k.a., informally "Community Wallets".</p>
<p>Unlike traditional systems, the core innovation here is that there is no whitelist or global governance structure. 0L Network had no pre-mine state, and designs such as "founder rewards" are antithetical to our design philosophy.</p>
<p>A Community Wallet (CW) is instantiated not only with a number of on-chain tools (smart contracts), but also with off-chain commitments. Without going into further detail, a user could create a CW (on chain), and ask for donations (off chain). Those donations would also serve as a way to index a Matching Donations list, which validators and other contributors could opt-into (more below).</p>
<p>Notably, this open system is probabilistic, it was known in advance that it was likely that this would be abused (and as you see below, it was). So there are a number of conditions a CW owner, opts-into by instantiating Donor Voice covenants on their account:</p>
<ul>
<li>That account can only transfer coins to a Slow Wallet</li>
<li>Proposed transfer takes three epochs (days) to finalize.</li>
<li>During this period, Donors to have the opportunity to veto a transaction.</li>
<li>Sequential vetoes to the account will freeze it from doing future transfers.</li>
<li>Since V6.9.0, Donor Voice enabled accounts are required to be multi-sigs.</li>
</ul>
<p>The astute reader will notice, the probabilistic equilibrium depends on players.</p>
<p>With an insufficient number of players observing Donor Voice accounts, or misplaced trust in observers of those accounts, abuse will take place. This is not a surprise, and was known from the start. A trade-off in playing open games.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="match-index">Match Index<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#match-index" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Match Index" title="Direct link to Match Index">​</a></h4>
<p>In many blockchains there is programmatic removal of coins from supply. Without going into much detail, there are cases when a user should pay competitively for a resource (e.g. transaction ordering), but the cost of providing that value is not proportional to the fee. One pattern is to exclude from the new network - colloquially, “burn” - the difference, and remove it from circulation permanently (see for example Ethereum's EIP 1551).</p>
<p>Typically the reason for burning instead of redirecting, is that burns prevent a kind of exploit loop where attackers can harvest the redirect. This is true, but it is also a missed opportunity and 0L Network proposed a market driven experiment.</p>
<p>There is also an opt-in alternative built into all accounts, that allows any user to redirect burns attributed to their accounts to community programs. Strictly speaking: a Donor Voice enabled account usually elects to be a part of Matching Index. This means instead of permanently removing the excess coins, validators can use them to fund any community's programs.</p>
<p>When a miner or validator opted into making matching donations to a CW, certain regular programmatic removal of coins, would instead recycle coins to the Match Index. (People have compared this mechanism as akin to implementations in the crypto industry of Quadratic Finance, without the quadratic nature of votes).</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-equilibrium">The Equilibrium<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#the-equilibrium" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Equilibrium" title="Direct link to The Equilibrium">​</a></h3>
<p>The intersection of Community Wallets and Matching Donations was designed to create a healthy tension:</p>
<ul>
<li>Community Wallet Creation: Any community member has the power to create a Community Wallet, allowing for community participation in a diverse set of initiatives.</li>
<li>Influence through Donations: By donating to these wallets, individual community members can influence the allocation of matching donations. This system is designed to encourage community support.</li>
</ul>
<p>To the objection that more controls were necessary, the old adage of payment processing applies: "I can promise you zero fraud, as long as you receive zero payments".</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="boundaries-and-consequences">Boundaries and Consequences<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#boundaries-and-consequences" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Boundaries and Consequences" title="Direct link to Boundaries and Consequences">​</a></h4>
<p>We've mentioned on-chain constraints to these accounts. It's also worth highlighting that the economic game involving community wallet, exists offline too. The blockchain serves as a coordination layer for the game, it is not the boundary of the game. All users of community wallet tooling should have the expectation that the laws and norms of society continue to apply (code is not law).</p>
<ul>
<li>Social: Community backlash or loss of trust among peers.</li>
<li>Legal: Potential legal actions based on the severity and nature of the manipulation.</li>
<li>Hard Fork: In extreme cases, the network might undergo a hard fork — a significant change to the protocol software and database which contain any rules the new network participants choose to enforce, for example: dropping accounts.</li>
</ul>
<h1>The Exploits</h1>
<p>This section explains the three types of abuse by community wallet creators which led to the hard fork decision.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="harvesting">Harvesting<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#harvesting" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Harvesting" title="Direct link to Harvesting">​</a></h3>
<p>The Harvesting exploit involves skewing the matching donations algorithm by donating to a community wallet under the control of one validator with the only purpose of collecting coins from unsuspecting Match Index donors.</p>
<ul>
<li>Harvesting is the act of creating a Community Wallet, then:<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>Creating multiple accounts (usually Validators)</li>
<li>Programming them to funnel their donations and locked coins to the CW they control.</li>
<li>By doing so, the bad actors are increasing their CW balance while also creating the perception their Community Wallet is highly valued and directing more donations from the rest of the validators and the community as a whole.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The image below is an example of the harvesting exploit. The blue nodes (validators), made AUTOPAY (blue lines) to a community wallet (orange node). In the case presented below, you can see two CWs that the validators that participated in the Sybil attack donated to (one above the validators, one below):</li>
</ul>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdDv0XeO11HLUR0NFbfKZkIMu33cTFNOtVs8jrwbHF45XecHE4tZO7MGQBUeeOIHGUAXh6G2cB5oqCxKdHVsRQh41wjG5r0OIEthoJwlz2-HYC78Ic5EDcNfp8a7sYfq9X6VXbVogCm3nyWrqYs9NljeDqT?key=UdkA8jBMllBve2WagZXXwA" alt="image" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="spraying">Spraying<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#spraying" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Spraying" title="Direct link to Spraying">​</a></h3>
<p>Spraying exploits circumvent the standard Slow Wallet time-locking algorithm by dividing payments into several Slow Wallets.</p>
<ul>
<li>By design, a Community Wallet only makes payments to a Slow Wallet.<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>Coins that are sent from CW to a SW first enter a “bucket” of “locked” coins.</li>
<li>They vest and then eventually transition to an unlocked state at a rate of 35,000 coins per epoch.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Spraying is the act of creating multiple Slow Wallets and then sending CW_PAYMENT to them in parallel. Doing so linearly increases the number of unlocked coins. Instead of the allowed 35k unlocked coins per epoch, this exploit multiplies the effect by the number of slow wallets involved in the exploit.</li>
<li>In the image below, the purple nodes represent slow wallets, and the green lines represent CW_PAYMENTs. In this case 2773 payment events were made to 433 slow wallets.<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>That means that every epoch, the owner of that network accumulated 15.1 million unlocked coins.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdedjYc4qNdnT7RzmvLX2vZNgrF0SiobpUAFrQT-X3k69OxssdhXIE0FXbblYocdKintniwjcMx9tde51PD587GAJaABy6J8rFkwQgnClMVj_KH1tHTvC5YBFvCJJMB2ssQGrBiW3jPRR9lq8EXwBjyinQ?key=UdkA8jBMllBve2WagZXXwA" alt="image" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="transfer-bug">Transfer Bug<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#transfer-bug" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Transfer Bug" title="Direct link to Transfer Bug">​</a></h3>
<p>A regression to the codebase was introduced during the v6.9.0 upgrade.</p>
<ul>
<li>The codebase regression manifested in the ability of a CW to make ordinary transfers. This meant bypassing all Donor Voice governance including donor observability, and restricting to Slow Wallets.</li>
<li>The bug exploit can be seen in the image below with the red lines (transfers) from the CW (orange) to the nodes around it. In this particular case, you can see it exhibits also the first (multiple validators donate to it) and second exploits (making many payments to a multitude of Slow Wallets).</li>
</ul>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdg4tqkagkrHnHtGSOaOQgul_UDCLG2v1RFp3R1eKigc8Y3Psx6XsAeClqxwkF2nnvSFciXTP2hslnlOvMZiw2EaatK0dacqEncm2JRL3-W9c6xQOTbNTcbYoRgA1Aj-1Pl6VPW3i0I3WFkt-kDtO8B9ION?key=UdkA8jBMllBve2WagZXXwA" alt="image" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h1>CASE 1 Principal Exploit</h1>
<p>We will not cover each exploit in detail. However CASE 1 is exceptional because of the exploit size, there were approximately 3,614,811,756 (3.6 Billion) unlocked coins in possession of an individual (the largest unlocked coin stake by perhaps 30x). This is approximately 3.6% of the network supply.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="principal-accounts-involved">Principal Accounts involved<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#principal-accounts-involved" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Principal Accounts involved" title="Direct link to Principal Accounts involved">​</a></h3>
<p>There are many hundreds of accounts created by a single exploiter. This is verifiable by observing the path of account creation from a seed set of a few accounts.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXfiR_6nWttmM-i-0e5digE-8N3Z3HfFC1cQZtQR0Jy3imt67q44yYlFVMgKsp7vJN1iP6af1pfNBxbGQdy3kF7wBJrmEstINS4NaTCorV3tks6jtYr8kemVaK_f_u3W_9aGiB06Q6xLnVFIQLj_tiO9KWyy?key=UdkA8jBMllBve2WagZXXwA" alt="image" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>If the relationships of these few nodes are expanded, the flow of funds goes through these nodes:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXd2GfTBgsrE6jEFLkeSFOyQJjaRaNyQb5FuBgV1ExEoMjf489bfdS9WKX4o8B7khcS_ibHawRgYAvZLInFWt76e6heG-Y24kA5XrT-W_oWzZ5Nuz1jj1Je42ou5bEACLroPMZgszHp3EDoNQccJCcv2bCE?key=UdkA8jBMllBve2WagZXXwA" alt="image" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="sham-community-programs">Sham Community Programs<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#sham-community-programs" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Sham Community Programs" title="Direct link to Sham Community Programs">​</a></h4>
<p>The community wallets involved in this case are:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>7B61439A88060096213AC4F5853B598E</code></li>
<li><code>5E68026887147DE0EA9CA90962C25A41</code></li>
<li><code>97DCBC6BFAA7EDF00F9002DAAED49C46</code></li>
</ul>
<p>There is no information publicly available about these "community" programs. Different from other credible and well regarded programs in the community. Their principal source of funding was from "validators" nodes which the individual publicly associated themselves with. Due to the nature of Match Index (described above), many other validators became unwitting contributors to these accounts (the "harvesting" exploit).</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="sybil-validator-accounts">Sybil Validator Accounts<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/scorpions-claw-proposal#sybil-validator-accounts" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Sybil Validator Accounts" title="Direct link to Sybil Validator Accounts">​</a></h4>
<p>Community wallets could not reasonably accumulate much capital unless they solicited donations from many people. But if an individual had acquired access to many "validators" with high reward potential, they could do so. (Note, acquiring multiple validators was also outside the stated norms of the community. Several validators were notified publicly that you should not try to run multiple validators even though you might be able to get around some of the constraints).</p>
<p>In this case, the exploiter had ownership of the following validator addresses:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>6DA2B828F3018637379203940C639A95</code></li>
<li><code>15B291FFCA97895D726E8AA9A5BE6A2A</code></li>
<li><code>5DC8C3878E99E9FD12EBDEFA1803D332</code></li>
<li><code>C5162C65FDE8C9D9CA9B564E41A54003</code></li>
<li><code>988B8C3B7E55B6E5126884E02C8F166E</code></li>
<li><code>7D299BF3D624E937C23302D8B5E3A1B2</code></li>
<li><code>99E4EE712E2A57F694344D288A0FC27A</code></li>
<li><code>9F1D8C66883768F167A097FF4C58DE88</code></li>
<li><code>C0FFEE1A3393516D27B72B28464EAA5F</code></li>
</ul>
<h1>The Hard Fork Goals</h1>
<p>Once validators realized the magnitude of the exploit, they and core contributors responded by stopping their nodes preferring to await a full analysis and recommendation.</p>
<p>The recommendation here is to perform a hard fork of the 0L Network, which maintains all properties of the canonical chain except that it does not migrate the accounts involved in the abuse of the system’s hardcoded rules and prevents the abuse of those hardcoded rules from taking place again.</p>
<p>Punishment is not an end-goal. The recommendation is to simply remove abusive accounts, while perhaps setting a non-binding social precedent signaling that a decentralized group of validators are capable of taking, and willing to take, coordinated action to prevent abuse and will not run software that allows abuse.</p>
<h1>The Process</h1>
<p>The first part of the process involved defining the exploit types. The effort had three key objectives: ensure accuracy, capture as much questionable activity as possible, and avoid penalizing innocent parties all while still being deterministic.</p>
<p>The Goals were to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Find all the community wallets that participated in the defined exploits.</li>
<li>For each of them, via pattern matching, identify and collect a list of the nodes that participated in the scheme.</li>
<li>Identify edge cases where the common patterns did not apply or the scheme operator attempted to obfuscate their actions or balance by spreading nodes via common “superspreaders” like the Discord onboarders.</li>
<li>Ensure no common, widely known accounts were present on the list such as Discord onboarders.</li>
<li>Leave every harvesting case with a single validator node (both as a show of grace and to reward their legitimate contribution to the network).</li>
<li>Applying a 200K LIBRA balance threshold to reduce the impact to innocent parties who might be caught up accidentally in the exploit. This approach led to 45.58% of the accounts being excluded from further examination, ensuring the focus of remediation on more chief offenders (see table A in appendix).</li>
<li>A single database command should generate a list of accounts without human intervention.</li>
</ol>
<p>This whole process was written in several Cypher language (graph DB) queries and packaged into a Python tool that can be run by anyone to produce an identical checksum of the final list. This tool and the queries have been made public in the following directory on GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/0LNetworkCommunity/scorpions-claws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/0LNetworkCommunity/scorpions-claws</a>.</p>
<h1>The Result</h1>
<ul>
<li>436 accounts excluded from new network</li>
<li>Total LIBRA excluded from new network (“burned”): 3,768,939,592</li>
<li>Circulating LIBRA burned: 1,419,359,988</li>
<li>Locked LIBRA burned: 640,266,766</li>
<li>Community Wallet LIBRA burned: 1,709,312,837</li>
<li>Community Wallet excluded from new network: 6</li>
<li>Historical validator accounts excluded from new network: 11</li>
</ul>
<h1>Actions Needed by The Coin Holders</h1>
<p>No action is required by community members who were not involved in the exploits. The transition to the hard fork and all subsequent version upgrades will occur seamlessly and automatically.</p>
<h1>Other Mitigations in Place</h1>
<p>What does the future look like and what more needs to be done?</p>
<ul>
<li>The Bug exploit was fixed in January 2024 in an on-chain upgrade.</li>
<li>A new off-chain monitoring infrastructure will be built post v7.<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>This will improve network visualization and investigative capabilities. The tools that have been developed and utilized during this exploit analysis, will be available soon for public use.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>A dedicated Community Wallets page in explorer will provide valuable insights and live CW activity.<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>The community and contributors will continue to report any discovered exploits, rather than taking advantage of them to the detriment of the rest of the community.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>There is no more easy money left.<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>A majority of the exploits occurred during a time in the evolution of the network where exploits like harvesting could be rewarded. That time has passed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h1>Acknowledgments</h1>
<p>Special thanks to the Scorpion's Claw task force and all the contributors who worked tirelessly over weeks to resolve these issues on behalf of the extended community. Your commitment to the network is greatly appreciated, and the community is very thankful for your efforts.</p>
<p>A very sincere and heartfelt thank you also to the wider community for your patience and support throughout this process.</p>
<h1>Appendix</h1>
<p>Scorpion’s Claw Farm Report: <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/e/2PACX-1vQXu7IISWJIAYQ1OG--ETtdaqE7tYG5Gs0kxDkwfRWZAD0W7SFVdb_EgoN8IqHyTj3DXIhF1okYLFT2/pub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://docs.google.com/document/d/e/2PACX-1vQXu7IISWJIAYQ1OG--ETtdaqE7tYG5Gs0kxDkwfRWZAD0W7SFVdb_EgoN8IqHyTj3DXIhF1okYLFT2/pub</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>fork</category>
            <category>proposal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Team Arctika Recommendation]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[To survive, the 0L Network needs to solve two problems. We need:]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>To survive, the 0L Network needs to solve two problems. We need</strong>:</p>
<ol>
<li>Abundant capital for security, and</li>
<li>Abundant capital for recruiting talent.</li>
</ol>
<p>And if possible, we should solve these problems in a fashion that does not worsen the inequality between members of the community.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="much-more-capital-is-needed">Much More Capital Is Needed<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation#much-more-capital-is-needed" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Much More Capital Is Needed" title="Direct link to Much More Capital Is Needed">​</a></h2>
<p>The crypto headwinds are significant: Regulatory pressure, fraud, scammers and a macro economic environment that favors the bears. If the network wants to survive the next decade, without any inflation, it needs to reserve a large portion of the network capital for future purposes. We will need to provision a greater amount than our peers who have inflation. We are of the opinion that the proportion should be as close to 80% / 20% as possible (the math resembles that of venture fund economics). While we strived for that goal, we weren't able to reach that number without massive disruption to multiple user groups. We finally arrived at a 70/30 ratio (70% for growth and ecosystem; 30% held by community members today), which gets us functionally close to the original goal, without system wide disruption of stakeholders.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-much-is-necessary-for-the-infrastructure-escrow-fund-ief">How much is necessary for the Infrastructure Escrow Fund (IEF)?<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation#how-much-is-necessary-for-the-infrastructure-escrow-fund-ief" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How much is necessary for the Infrastructure Escrow Fund (IEF)?" title="Direct link to How much is necessary for the Infrastructure Escrow Fund (IEF)?">​</a></h2>
<p>We can estimate that, in order to attract validators, the network will have to pay each validator US$4-5k per month (this is consistent with what validators are paid in mature networks with smoothly operating software). In our interviews with professional validators, we arrived at $4,200 as our baseline. See the data in the table, below:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://docs.openlibra.io/assets/images/validator-opportunity-cost-6d33742dd471b2246c49579b0b543e48.png" width="1024" height="558" class="img_ev3q">
The Team agrees that we need to provision for another 7 years of network operations. We’re roughly three years into the network’s life cycle at this point in time (1 year in testnet, followed by almost 2 years since Genesis). Altogether, we should make it through at least the first 10 years of the network.</p>
<p>Of course, translating a token with no market value into monthly USD amounts requires some assumptions about value. We must take a conservative approach on market cap, for "all weather conditions". Despite what we’ve seen with some of our peer networks, we can't reasonably say that the base case for networks is a valuation of $1B+ over the next 7 years. Likewise a network worth less than $50M for many years likely leads to extinction. So, the calculations we made assumed a $100M market cap, from which a token value could be extrapolated; this seemed like a reasonable base-case (which could be substantiated further).
At that intersection: 100 validators earning $4,200 per month over 7 years, with a network on average worth $100m, the result is approx 35% of network capital needs to be pre-diluted for sufficient safety.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://docs.openlibra.io/assets/images/infrastructure-escrow-pledge-sensitivity-ee5240be9581972cbbfaf518bfff522c.png" width="1024" height="623" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="over-allocation">Over-allocation<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation#over-allocation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Over-allocation" title="Direct link to Over-allocation">​</a></h3>
<p>The formula above, and our approach to erring on the side of more rewards, may lead to over-allocation of OPEX instead of CAPEX type activities; so there must be a provision for over allocation (i.e. if the network is persistently worth more than $100M).</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="policy-for-over-allocation">Policy for Over Allocation<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation#policy-for-over-allocation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Policy for Over Allocation" title="Direct link to Policy for Over Allocation">​</a></h4>
<p>The IEF is designed to continue with the V5 policy, that overspending can be burnt: i.e. reclaimed capital. The burn can optionally be "recycled" by validators by sending to an algorithmic matching contract, which distributes to Donor Directed wallets (aka community wallets) which have received the most donations (biased for most recent donations). We recommend this policy continue, such that over-allocation to OPEX and infrastructure, doesn't penalize growth capital (CAPEX). This is compatible with the Proof-of-Fee design where, for example, every epoch there can be a consistent drawdown from infra-escrow, and only the net is paid to validators, and the overallocation is burnt per the policy above.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="who-can-contribute">Who can contribute?<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation#who-can-contribute" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Who can contribute?" title="Direct link to Who can contribute?">​</a></h2>
<p>Some category of participants need to pay for these proposed changes. This requires a pragmatic, and not an emotional solution: <em><strong>What does the repeated game need for success?</strong></em>
We elected to eliminate some options outright:&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Carpe miners</strong>: There is not enough capital to meaningfully tax those users. Any tax would be symbolic.</li>
<li><strong>Worker slow wallets</strong> (e.g., beneficiaries of FTW, Hustle Karma, and other community bounties): Again there is not enough to tax, that would meaningfully contribute.</li>
<li><strong>Community Wallets</strong>: That’s a bigger topic so, see below</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-exclude-community-wallets">Why Exclude Community Wallets?<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation#why-exclude-community-wallets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Why Exclude Community Wallets?" title="Direct link to Why Exclude Community Wallets?">​</a></h3>
<p>There's a lot of misunderstanding about Community Wallets – and the concept is very important to the project for several reasons, not the least of which is regulatory compliance.&nbsp;
0L has no centralized treasury, by design, and for regulatory compliance it has been recommended that we never implement one. Community wallets are an emergent property of the network. The wallets have typically&nbsp; been created to fund programs for the benefit of the community. Part of their role is to safeguard capital for future uses. The vast majority of them have some language related to: a) safeguarding capital for future use in the network, b) deploying that capital. According to the disclosures of these accounts the capital is not used for personal or company enrichment.
Given their stated role, taxing the community wallets is taxing our growth capital. If you reduce the size of community wallets in favor of infrastructure escrow (IEF), you are reducing the amount of discretionary investment capital.&nbsp;
In the extreme case: If you tax community wallets 100% into the IEF, while we will solve problem one (security capital), we would fail on the second problem (there will be no funds to credibly attract future talent and entrepreneurship).1
We are left with charging the Validators.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-much-do-we-ask-validators-to-contribute">How much do we ask validators to contribute?<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation#how-much-do-we-ask-validators-to-contribute" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How much do we ask validators to contribute?" title="Direct link to How much do we ask validators to contribute?">​</a></h2>
<p>If we keep with the numbers above, Validators should contribute 80% of past rewards towards the future IEF. We think this is acceptable for two reasons: First, there is very little choice if we are to survive, and second, the historical payout was not reflective of market conditions and therefore equity favors adjustment.2</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="disproportionate-rewards">Disproportionate rewards<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation#disproportionate-rewards" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Disproportionate rewards" title="Direct link to Disproportionate rewards">​</a></h3>
<p>Our conclusions about the need to address equity were based on data. We conducted a survey to find out how much volunteers have contributed over time, and what is the approximate value of that work. We asked the same of validators, as well as engineers.
The results of our (limited3) research showed that, at the extremes, workers had a cost per coin that was up to 45X higher&nbsp; than the costs incurred by the Validators. Another way to look at it, the cost per coin (from lost wages and infrastructure payments) that pure Validators paid was 1/45 that of the top contributors (all rewards considered). That's about a 98% discount4, according to our research numbers. Paying more did not confer the workers any advantage in volume (they were not able to accumulate more share of the network).
After the dilution, Validators are still getting an extremely attractive proposition. Excluding outliers (0D for example) the typical validator accounts still have paid 87% less than the top 10 worker accounts.5 It would be inappropriate, however, to conclude that the workers have been given a superior deal. The vast majority of workers have the majority of their coins from validator work. And those accounts will also be contributing 80%. This can only be corrected by using the community wallets judiciously.
Despite the workers not being explicitly and mechanically taxed, they have already been (e.g., inflation). Even after this intervention, and considering possible uses of community wallets to "make-whole" these workers, in the best case the largest passive validators will have a 76% discount on cost per coin versus the lead engineers. While we can make it better, we can’t fix everything.
Lastly, the most committed Validators will partially reclaim their contributions to IEF if they commit to validating over the long term. By continuing to operate a Validator, a portion of those coins will come back to them. (Note this is the only group of community members that benefits from this mechanism.)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="budgeting-for-past-workers">Budgeting for past workers<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation#budgeting-for-past-workers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Budgeting for past workers" title="Direct link to Budgeting for past workers">​</a></h2>
<p>A related issue is also being addressed in conjunction with the tokenomics adjustment. Prior to the re-basing and the dilution and adjustments outlined above, the Tip Jar and Iqlusion FTW wallets will be distributed to workers. Note that these uses are consistent with the stated aims of the wallets and, at least in the case of the FTW wallet, the amounts should have already been paid out. Failure to pay those out prior to the re-basing would disadvantage those workers. Put another way, the Tip Jar (which 0D has already offered to community purposes), as well as the FTW wallet (which has not made monthly payouts as it was intended to) should "make-whole" the past workers.&nbsp;
We think the proposal increases equity but frankly the main purpose of the proposal is for survival. The increase in equity is a bonus. The only scenario in which everyone is equal is the collapse scenario which none of us want.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="budgeting-for-future-workers">Budgeting for future workers<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation#budgeting-for-future-workers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Budgeting for future workers" title="Direct link to Budgeting for future workers">​</a></h2>
<p>The remaining community programs should focus on the future. There is no formal mechanism, but they can be encouraged to do so by their donors (which are historically validators) through the governance changes to Donor Directed Wallets.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion-this-is-what-good-capital-looks-like">Conclusion: This is what Good Capital looks like<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation#conclusion-this-is-what-good-capital-looks-like" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion: This is what Good Capital looks like" title="Direct link to Conclusion: This is what Good Capital looks like">​</a></h2>
<p>We looked at many models of dilutions and fees. Asking validators to invest 80% of prior rewards into Infra Escrow, very cleanly (even serendipitously) allowed the network to have these properties:</p>
<ul>
<li>70/30 in favor of future network participants.</li>
<li>Have future capital for Opex (Infra Escrow) and Capex (Community Wallets) split evenly (out of the 70%) in the base case.</li>
<li>Reduce the gap between worker and validators to 1.3X from 16X.</li>
</ul>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://docs.openlibra.io/assets/images/summary-dilution-impacts-ead32ebbd61af21918efc0092585e7ee.png" width="1024" height="750" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>We think this allocation, with abundant amounts for future capital, which honors prior workers such that we can continue recruiting for future talent, and sets up all current participants for future success is <strong>unique and exemplary in the industry, and fulfills our mission of creating "good capital" and gives us the best shot at surviving and thriving.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="-team-arctika-alext-daniyal-lex-0d-ricoflan-wade--tpt-zmanian"><strong>– Team Arctika</strong> (AlexT, Daniyal, Lex, 0D, ricoflan, Wade | TPT, Zmanian)<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/team-arctika-recommendation#-team-arctika-alext-daniyal-lex-0d-ricoflan-wade--tpt-zmanian" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to -team-arctika-alext-daniyal-lex-0d-ricoflan-wade--tpt-zmanian" title="Direct link to -team-arctika-alext-daniyal-lex-0d-ricoflan-wade--tpt-zmanian">​</a></h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>**Note the Arctika Report was originally published to the 0L Network Discord on 23 May, 2023.&nbsp;See, <a href="https://discord.com/channels/833074824447655976/910315033672704090/1110679498288005130" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://discord.com/channels/833074824447655976/910315033672704090/1110679498288005130</a></em></p>
<p>===========end notes============</p>
<p>1&nbsp;That all said, there is an important recommendation we must make for community wallets. Keeping with the October poll, where the network expanded the governance of the Donor Directed wallets, to allow the donors to freeze accounts, this was underspecified. What happens with the frozen account? We think the natural conclusion is that the frozen account should get liquidated into a pro-rata share of the remaining qualifying donor directed wallets. We don't anticipate this will ever be done, but it's important for the game theory of multiparty negotiation of the uses of the community wallets.
2&nbsp;A key incident contributed to the second issue, the disparity in the history payouts to Validators. There is an acknowledgement that the Reward Auction in 0L was no longer viable after a partial upgrade in April 2022 (the baseline parameters were not updated after some other policies were updated).
3&nbsp;This was done via a Google Form that a number of members voluntarily completed, so it is based on self-reported data.
4&nbsp;We do recognize this is a generalization and may not apply to everyone across the distribution, but the data we gathered did support these numbers as a general matter.
5&nbsp;Note that our calculations showed that you could achieve equity between the groups, but only at the expense of diluting Validators by 98% – a non-starter.
6&nbsp;Note this “BEFORE” data is from the Cap Table research done by ricoflan in March 2023, so it is not current at the time of publication of this paper (23 May 2023).</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>econ</category>
            <category>proposal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2022 Governance Recap]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/october-2022-governance-recap</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/october-2022-governance-recap</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The 0L Community recently concluded its first round of collaborative, decentralized strategic planning. Starting first with rounds of guided discussion on the RadicalxChange Voice platform, the process culminated with a set of eight proposals for community vote. In this blog post, we’re going to take a brief look at the contents of those proposals and reflect on the outcomes of the vote.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 0L Community recently concluded its first round of collaborative, decentralized strategic planning. Starting first with rounds of guided discussion on the <a href="https://voice.radicalxchange.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RadicalxChange Voice</a> platform, the process culminated with a set of eight proposals for community vote. In this blog post, we’re going to take a brief look at the contents of those proposals and reflect on the outcomes of the vote.&nbsp;</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-voting-process">The Voting Process<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/october-2022-governance-recap#the-voting-process" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Voting Process" title="Direct link to The Voting Process">​</a></h2>
<p>Seven of the eight proposals gave voters a yes-or-no binary option for voting. The eighth proposal was comprised of four parts that needed to be voted on independently. The voting platform was RadicalxChange Voice, which gives all voters an equal amount of “credits”, which can be used to vote more than once for any proposal they feel strongly about, allowing them to express how committed they are to that result (note this factor is expressed below as “voting power” which expresses the total commitment of both positive and negative votes). Voters were not able to see the votes of the group as they cast their votes, and the voters could change their votes right up to the deadline.&nbsp;</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-proposals">The Proposals<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/october-2022-governance-recap#the-proposals" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Proposals" title="Direct link to The Proposals">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-2210-01-final-supply"><a href="http://openlibra.blog/2022/10/11/proposal-2210-1-final-supply/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Proposal 2210-01 Final Supply</a><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/october-2022-governance-recap#proposal-2210-01-final-supply" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to proposal-2210-01-final-supply" title="Direct link to proposal-2210-01-final-supply">​</a></h3>
<p><strong>Synopsis</strong>: Proposal 1022-01 is focused on stopping inflation within 0L, while creating a mechanism for funding ongoing validator incentives in the absence of issuance. There are three parts to the proposal: (1) stop issuance; (2) rebase the token; and (3) create and fund an Infrastructure Escrow community wallet to provide validator rewards. The proposal asks for a single vote on all three parts; the three parts are interconnected and dependent.</p>
<p><strong>Voting Result:</strong> This proposal passed by the largest margin (+134) and also showed the largest commitment of voting power (1,036 credits). Looking at the raw numbers in the voting, this proposal received the largest total number of positive votes and the highest number of voters.</p>
<p><strong>Comments</strong>: Clearly, this was the topic of greatest concern to the community. The large positive vote was a bit of a surprise given the complexity of this proposal (3 parts) and the significant impact it would have on the system’s tokenomics.&nbsp;</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-2210-02-proof-of-fee"><a href="http://openlibra.blog/2022/10/11/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Proposal 2210-02 Proof of Fee</a><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/october-2022-governance-recap#proposal-2210-02-proof-of-fee" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to proposal-2210-02-proof-of-fee" title="Direct link to proposal-2210-02-proof-of-fee">​</a></h3>
<p><strong>Synopsis</strong>: Proof of Fee could be used to partially replace 0L's current security model by adding new economic guarantees.</p>
<p><strong>Voting Result</strong>: Passed by a reasonable margin (+63) and received the second largest amount of voting power (579). A look at the raw data shows this proposal had the third-largest number of voters and received the largest number of negative votes.</p>
<p><strong>Comments</strong>: This was a highly technical question that is primarily of interest to validators (existing or potential). The high levels of commitment, combined with the median result in the voting margin, shows that there were strong opposing opinions about this. The large number of negative votes also shows this to be one of the most divisive proposed changes to the network’s technical architecture.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-2210-03-musical-chairs"><a href="http://openlibra.blog/2022/10/11/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Proposal 2210-03 Musical Chairs</a><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/october-2022-governance-recap#proposal-2210-03-musical-chairs" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to proposal-2210-03-musical-chairs" title="Direct link to proposal-2210-03-musical-chairs">​</a></h3>
<p><strong>Synopsis</strong>: Change the way the validator selection set is chosen so that performance and cost can be optimized in a competitive way..</p>
<p><strong>Voting Result</strong>: Passed with the smallest margin of any of the full proposals (+61) and showed a moderate amount of commitment in terms of voting power (191). A look at the raw data shows this proposal had the second-highest number of negative votes.</p>
<p><strong>Comments</strong>: Like proposal 1022-02, this proposal presents a highly technical question that is primarily of interest to validators (existing or potential). This passed, but by the smallest margin of the entire set of proposal, and with a significant number of negative votes, indicating that this proposal is likely the most controversial of the entire set.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-2210-04-repurpose-carpe"><a href="http://openlibra.blog/2022/10/11/proposal-2210-4-repurpose-carpe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Proposal 2210-04 Repurpose Carpe</a><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/october-2022-governance-recap#proposal-2210-04-repurpose-carpe" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to proposal-2210-04-repurpose-carpe" title="Direct link to proposal-2210-04-repurpose-carpe">​</a></h3>
<p><strong>Synopsis</strong>: Move the Carpe app away from building towers and use it for something else, maybe as an oracle for the network.</p>
<p><strong>Voting Result</strong>: Passed by with a reasonable margin (+74), but showed the second lowest amount of commitment in terms of voting power of any of the proposals (306). A look at the raw data shows this proposal had the second highest number of voters.</p>
<p><strong>Comments</strong>: A large number of voters with a low expenditure of voting power would indicate that while people had opinions on this proposal, they were not strongly held.&nbsp;</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-2210-05-revenue-binding-primitives"><a href="http://openlibra.blog/2022/10/11/proposal-2210-5-revenue-binding-primitives/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Proposal 2210-05 Revenue Binding Primitives</a><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/october-2022-governance-recap#proposal-2210-05-revenue-binding-primitives" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to proposal-2210-05-revenue-binding-primitives" title="Direct link to proposal-2210-05-revenue-binding-primitives">​</a></h3>
<p><strong>Synopsis</strong>: Tells the engineering team to make 0L protocol primitives that support a variety of payment functions that will be needed for future app development their top priority.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Voting Result</strong>: Passed by the second-largest margin (+85), but showed a relatively low amount of commitment in terms of voting power (335). A look at the raw data shows that there were no votes against this proposal, one of only two to pass without opposition.</p>
<p><strong>Comments</strong>: A non-controversial proposal that advocates for building tooling, this proposal passed easily.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-2210-06-faucets-for-workers"><a href="http://openlibra.blog/2022/10/11/proposal-2210-6-faucets-for-workers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Proposal 2210-06 Faucets for Workers</a><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/october-2022-governance-recap#proposal-2210-06-faucets-for-workers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to proposal-2210-06-faucets-for-workers" title="Direct link to proposal-2210-06-faucets-for-workers">​</a></h3>
<p><strong>Synopsis</strong>: Create faucet tooling for Community Wallets and others to create automated rewards.</p>
<p><strong>Voting Result</strong>: Passed with the smallest margin of any of the full proposals (+36) and showed the lowest commitment of voting power of any of the proposals (191). A look at the raw data shows this proposal had no negative votes, one of only two to pass without opposition.</p>
<p><strong>Comments</strong>: This proposal was non-controversial, but generated low engagement, suggesting that it is generally supported but not necessarily a top priority for the community.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-2210-07-donor-directed-community-wallets"><a href="http://openlibra.blog/2022/10/11/proposal-2210-7-donor-directed-community-wallets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Proposal 2210-07 Donor-Directed Community Wallets</a><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/october-2022-governance-recap#proposal-2210-07-donor-directed-community-wallets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to proposal-2210-07-donor-directed-community-wallets" title="Direct link to proposal-2210-07-donor-directed-community-wallets">​</a></h3>
<p><strong>Synopsis</strong>: Create better oversight of community wallets such that they are actually donor-directed, and have purpose-built multisignature features.</p>
<p><strong>Voting Result</strong>: Passed with the third highest margin of any of the full proposals (+76) and showed a moderate amount of commitment in terms of voting power (354). A look at the raw data shows this proposal had only one negative vote.</p>
<p><strong>Comments</strong>: The result here aligns with what we’ve been hearing in community conversations, namely, that community wallets, as designed, are underperforming and need to better support more complex governance.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-2210-08-infrastructure-escrow-fund"><a href="http://openlibra.blog/2022/10/11/proposal-2210-8-infrastructure-escrow-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Proposal 2210-08 Infrastructure Escrow Fund</a><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/october-2022-governance-recap#proposal-2210-08-infrastructure-escrow-fund" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to proposal-2210-08-infrastructure-escrow-fund" title="Direct link to proposal-2210-08-infrastructure-escrow-fund">​</a></h3>
<p><strong>Synopsis</strong>: This proposal asked voters to indicate how they wished the cost of the Infrastructure Escrow Fund to be allocated among the existing wallet holders. Voters could vote for, or against, charging each of four categories: Validators, Community Wallets, Carpe Miners, or Basic Wallet Holders.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Voting Result</strong>:&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<p>Validators: +67 (487 commitments)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Community Wallets: +58 (446 commitments)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Carpe Miners: +1 (147 commitments)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Basic Wallet Holders: 0 (156 commitments)</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Comments</strong>: There is a clear and strong preference for diluting the Validators and Community Wallets. The results of this vote will be used to create the formula used for diluting all the wallet holders, a process needed to implement the Infrastructure Escrow Fund (as per Proposal 1022-1 Final Supply).</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="where-do-we-go-from-here">Where do we go from here?<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/october-2022-governance-recap#where-do-we-go-from-here" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Where do we go from here?" title="Direct link to Where do we go from here?">​</a></h2>
<p>It is important to note that all the proposals presented in this process were signaling proposals, that is, they were created to help define consensus and formulate direction and strategy for the network. None of the proposals resulted in immediate changes to the network, either online or offline. Rather, these proposals form the basis for taking further action to accomplish the strategic goals defined by this vote. Given that, it is hard to categorize any of these proposals as winners or losers; rather, they all served as indicators of future direction and required significant additional effort from the community.</p>
<p>Stepping back a moment and looking at the sum of the proposals on the slate:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Despite some controversy displayed in the discussions around the Final Supply proposal (Proposal 2210-01), the vote revealed a clear mandate to move forward. The proposal was sweeping in its proposed changes and included (1) stopping issuance, (2) rebasing the token, and (3) creating the Infrastructure Escrow Fund. Implementing these changes would represent a significant change in direction for the tokenomics of the project. This is our strongest indication of direction from the community and therefore deserves to be prioritized.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Given the results of the votes on the four parts of the Infrastructure Escrow Fund (Proposal 1022-08), the re-basing should result almost exclusively in the dilution of Validators and Community Wallets, with only a token contribution coming from the Carpe Miners. Basic Wallet holders (i.e., workers, other token holders) would not be impacted.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Two of the proposals aimed squarely at our validator operations, Proof of Fee (1022-02) and Musical Chairs (1022-03), gave us more ambiguous results and better reflected the divided discussions that occurred in the run-up to the vote. Though both of these changes passed, it seems clear that there should be further discussion and perhaps refinement of these proposals to achieve better consensus.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The question of what to do with the Carpe app in light of the changes proposed above also remains open. While the proposal to repurpose Carpe (1022-04) passed, it showed a lack of commitment, which may reflect the fact that while the community recognizes that Carpe has value and that we should do something with it, no one is exactly sure what the best course of action is for the future of the app.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The remaining three proposals (Revenue Binding Primitives, Faucets for Workers, and Donor Directed Community Wallets), were all non-controversial, and the results were consistent with that. The low levels of commitment on proposals 1022-05 and 1022-06 would indicate that these matters, while non-controversial, are also not priorities. In contrast, the higher levels of engagement on 1022-07 (Donor-Directed Community Wallets), would indicate that this proposal should be moved forward more quickly.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>At the end of all this, the answer to the question “where do we go from here?” depends on whether the individual members of our community can move forward with collaborative action. The successful completion of this community strategy development process, while meaningful, is all for naught if the community does not step up and commit the resources needed to operationalize the strategy.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>governance</category>
            <category>proposal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proof of Fee - Part 2]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[From empirical evidence over the last five years, we have seen few malicious attacks by validators; clearly something is working. We don't want to break something that is working. What we want to evaluate is whether we can make it sustainably work at a lower cost.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar" style="color:#393A34;background-color:#f6f8fa"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">In [Part 1 of this paper](http://openlibra.blog/2022/10/15/proof-of-fee-part-1/) we laid the foundations for Proof of Fee. Some of the ideas expressed there may be different from what you have seen elsewhere, and we do urge you to read that before you begin here. In Part 2 of this paper, below, we get into the mechanics and implementation details of Proof-of-Fee (PoF).</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>From empirical evidence over the last five years, we have seen few malicious attacks by validators; clearly something is working. We don't want to break something that is working. What we want to evaluate is whether we can make it sustainably work at a lower cost.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="gaming-it-out">Gaming it out<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#gaming-it-out" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Gaming it out" title="Direct link to Gaming it out">​</a></h2>
<p>In part 1, we concluded that estimating the security of the network in monetary terms is not directly correlated to the financial costs of stakes. PBFT as a consensus algorithm has compelling built-in security properties. Plus, launching a PBFT network necessarily starts from a root of trust, and this can be reinforced by validator admission policies that reduce likelihood of Sybil attacks.</p>
<p>The central question is this: How is a large bond staked by a diverse group of agents contributing to security? Is it really necessary?</p>
<p>Before we can evaluate how the high bonding works on PBFT, we should define which actors can be Byzantine. Are we trying to be safe from the everyman who goes rogue, or a madman? The deterrence strategies you would apply in those two situations are not the same.</p>
<p>If you goal is educating the initially honest validators on what is expected, then we would argue that swift and sure penalties are much more important than highly severe but rare penalties. When it comes to madmen, however, economic guarantees are marginal at best.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="deterrence-is-in-the-mind">Deterrence is in the mind<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#deterrence-is-in-the-mind" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Deterrence is in the mind" title="Direct link to Deterrence is in the mind">​</a></h3>
<p>Swift and sure penalties train actors in cause and effect and teach what is expected. A quick time-out is a much better training method for wayward children than a rare but severe strapping.&nbsp; In theory, high stakes penalties for unlikely events are a way of achieving compliant behavior without having to wait for the parties to learn (by way of experiencing the penalties) but they work mostly through perceptions and may easily backfire. The rare strapping, for example, may teach the child that punishment is random and parents are not to be trusted.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Similarly, capital punishment is a pyschological game, not a device meant to train someone across a series of events. Moreover, for something as extreme as capital punishment to work well, it needs to be placed within a context of other swift and sure penalties. That is, the credibility of maximal punishment also depends on consistency. Catch people for spray painting graffiti and others may be deterred from more serious crimes, but let graffiti take over and all punishment will come to be doubted no matter the crime.</p>
<p>Punishments for unlikely events work within a context of swift and sure penalties for smaller events mostly by preventing good agents from "breaking bad". Normal people learn what is expected and don’t doubt that big deviations will be punished.</p>
<p>Severe penalties don’t necessarily deter people that don't evaluate the punishment in the same way (e.g., the mentally ill, the North Korean nuclear program), or engage in a repeated game with the state where the punishment is not dispensed (e.g., serial killers, organized crime, Iranian nuclear program). Policy designers may assume incorrectly that the only way to handle these situations is to ratchet rare punishments yet higher. Applying maximal punishment out of the context of learning may seem rational to deter a madman, but to the everyman it is terror and leads to distrust and learned helplessness.&nbsp;</p>
<p>What does this mean for blockchain?&nbsp;</p>
<p>An attack by a sophisticated and resourced or irrational malicious actor is not going to be deterred by high bonding. In practice, slashing is never complete because of the fear this creates in normal, and normally good, actors. As implemented in Tendermint, for example, a defector does not lose their entire stake in a single "slashing" event commensurate with the damage done because that would drive out good actors. Moreover, a well-resourced attacker knows this, and isn't particularly deterred (and in fact could subsidize a one-time attack with winnings along the way). The solution, however, isn’t to slash more.</p>
<p>There are always madmen that want to see the world burn; economic guarantees are not effective against them. The only thing that deters the madman, at any price, is the validator admission policy, as we describe below. Modest, swift, and sure penalties will achieve what can be achieved and at lower cost than “capital punishment” style slashing. We should leverage this in our favor to secure PBFT blockchains, at the appropriate cost.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-town-of-robbers-is-no-town-at-all">A town of robbers is no town at all<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#a-town-of-robbers-is-no-town-at-all" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to A town of robbers is no town at all" title="Direct link to A town of robbers is no town at all">​</a></h3>
<p>There's another argument often advanced for high bonds: Humans are not inherently honest ergo, we should assume people on the internet are out to rob the chain. This may be a perfectly reasonable philosophy but, in the specific case of PBFT, it's unlikely to be destabilizing.</p>
<p>Silvio Micali has a thought experiment; it goes like this: Why would anyone move into a neighborhood or town where the vast majority of people were thieves? Certainly no good actor. In fact, not even the robbers would want to live there! These are places that, by definition, cannot exist. This is called the "honesty assumption" of PBFT and PBFT algorithm provides a guarantee. If you want to reorganize the already committed blocks, you'll need ⅔rds of the validator set to go along with it. Certainly it's possible that ⅔rds of the validator set could act against the will of one party or the entirety of the accounts on chain, but it begs two questions: (1) How does a network even arrive to the point of having ⅔ malicious actions? and (2) Are we sure an honest community can't recover from this?</p>
<p>Since PBFT networks start from a root of trust and continue to reinforce the norms of behavior, it seems that the deterrent to this problem is not economic, but rather in the validator credentialing process. The ways this is implemented are diverse. We’ve seen multiple approaches, from a foundation or a company signing contracts (with testnet winners), or a decentralized vouching from the existing validators, or coin voting for validator admission.</p>
<p>Moreover, there is also a way for account holders to recover: They can fork the validators out. Forking is another deterrent to a cabal of malicious agents. If you reorg the blocks against the will of the account holders by creating a fork, it may be trivial for the account holders to continue from where the fork branched off, with a new validator set. This is considered "weak subjectivity", and informal in the eyes of certain blockchain designers, but it doesn't prevent it from being a real deterrent, since it only needs to exist in the mind of the malicious actor. All that effort by the madman will be for naught. (To be clear this property doesn't neatly generalize to all blockchain consensus algorithms).</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="cartels-are-unstable">Cartels are unstable<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#cartels-are-unstable" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Cartels are unstable" title="Direct link to Cartels are unstable">​</a></h3>
<p>Lastly, advocates of high bonding rates might say it's trivial to turn good actors bad – you can just bribe people to join a cartel. However, that argument fails to consider that bad agents also face challenges. Coordination in adversarial space is a hard problem and this also applies to malicious agents attempting to form a cartel.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Cartels are not monopolists, though they try to achieve the maximum profit as if they were one. The trouble with cartels is that the dominant strategy of the cartel member is to cheat, not only once, but repeatedly. One defector from the cartel can reap the rewards of the monopoly price at a cost to other cartel members (not the consumer). And cheating in the repeated game quickly destabilizes the cartel. Plus, if your cartel operates outside the law or norms, is there any reason to expect a cartel member to respect the cartel's agreement? We know this from the behavior of other malicious cartels (think: drugs, mafia), which are rarely stable. The stable cartels that come to mind are those rare exceptions supported by governments (think: OPEC, American Medical Association).</p>
<p>So, if you are planning a long range attack on a blockchain, you'd better be sure that you are the monopolist and that you control all the nodes, otherwise you will be left holding the bag. This is a very expensive proposition, and likely loss-making. The cartel argument is a distraction; though one-time colluding attacks in PBFT can happen at a cost and uncertainty to the participants, sustaining collusion is another matter.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proof-of-fee-auctioning-consensus-seats">Proof of Fee: Auctioning Consensus Seats<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#proof-of-fee-auctioning-consensus-seats" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Proof of Fee: Auctioning Consensus Seats" title="Direct link to Proof of Fee: Auctioning Consensus Seats">​</a></h2>
<p>Given what we've seen above, a lot of the deterrence is already baked into the nature of the PBFT game and that deterrence is largely independent of the price. The madman attack is taken care of by admission controls, not economics. The cartel scenario is a red-herring. The economic guarantees seem to only be needed to keep honest people… honest.&nbsp;</p>
<p>So our provocation is this: What's the optimal price for the <em>social surplus</em>, so that everyone wins?</p>
<p>Proof of fee (PoF) is based on a premise: Let’s create equivalents of the bonding, staking, and slashing process by simply charging the equivalent cost of capital through an admission fee.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="problem-definition">Problem Definition<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#problem-definition" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Problem Definition" title="Direct link to Problem Definition">​</a></h3>
<p>The PoF protocol assumes that all revenues to the chain belong to all the token holders. As such, transaction fees are not a property right of the operators (validators). We assume that blockchains intend to be self-sufficient (or better), where sufficient revenues exist to pay for the consensus costs. As discussed in Part 1, because future blockspace is likely to become abundant (due to engineering advances), the blockchain must either develop other revenue streams besides blockspace, or become more cost efficient. For the cost-conscious token holders, the key question is: For a given level of security, how much do token holders have to pay to validators?</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="first-approach-a-reverse-auction">First Approach: A Reverse Auction<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#first-approach-a-reverse-auction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to First Approach: A Reverse Auction" title="Direct link to First Approach: A Reverse Auction">​</a></h3>
<p>On all blockchains, nodes are competing in an auction of compute power. What if we turned the usual blockchain auction upside down?</p>
<p>Our first attempt at a delegation-less and stake-free economic system is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reverse_auction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reverse auction</a>. Reverse auctions are also called procurement auctions, such that an enterprise has their orders for materials delivered at the lowest cost. In our case, the enterprise is the blockchain and the provider is the validator node.</p>
<p>One could set up an auction as follows: At the start of an upcoming epoch (period of blocks) a node which is selling compute power (to the blockchain for consensus) states the minimum reward they are willing to receive for the services at the end of the epoch. The X number nodes with lowest bids get admitted to the validator set.</p>
<p>The reverse auction model is attractive, namely for its simplicity. Alas, however, it is too simple. Simply agreeing to take a low fee, and subsequently being allowed to enter the validator set is not sufficient in permissionless and adversarial environments. We would really be pushing the limits on the guarantees of PBFT, since we really have the nothing-at-stake problem in this design.</p>
<p>The limitation of the above design is that there is no actual cost to enter the agreement with the blockchain. In such a simple reverse auction, the validator can bid a low fee but never deliver on services. In a group of carefully vetted operators, this would be fine. But in an adversarial scenario, or a scenario where the abilities of the validators are indeterminate (amateurs), there should be a real cost to non-performance.&nbsp; We can imagine ways in which a madman might wreak havoc in a number of ways (a "split brain" attack for instance). But as we said above, preventing this belongs in the domain of the validator credentialing. The real threat is operator incompetence. Suppose a validator bids the maximal amount, and simply forgets to start the machine at the right time. This hurts the network in a meaningful way, it will slow down and ultimately halt, and at no cost to the validator. The risks are asymmetric, and leads to a type of prisoner's dilemma game. Empirically this has been the greatest threat to PBFT networks: Amateurism.&nbsp;</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="pricing-carelessness-with-a-forward-auction">Pricing Carelessness With A Forward Auction<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#pricing-carelessness-with-a-forward-auction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Pricing Carelessness With A Forward Auction" title="Direct link to Pricing Carelessness With A Forward Auction">​</a></h3>
<p>In almost all markets there are entry fees, some are explicit, and some are implicit. In Bitcoin, there is a hardware capital cost. In DPoS, there is a bond. How else can we charge an entry fee?</p>
<p>As a reverse auction is not ideal, we'll need to go back to an ordinary (forward) auction, where the blockchain is selling consensus seats. In this case, the validators need to know what they are bidding on, and know what the cost of non-performance is.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The design is equally simple: The blockchain must determine the baseline reward it is willing to offer validators for the epoch, and validators pay to gain admission.</p>
<p>As an example, suppose the blockchain offers 10 coins per validator every epoch and suppose that the validator is profitable at 4 coins to validate (with 4 being the real dollar cost evaluated in coins at current dollar-coin exchange rates). Validators, functioning as bidders, would then bid on the seats in consensus, e.g. pay in advance up to 6 coins, for the benefit of winning 10, and thus netting 4 coins. This is functionally equivalent to the reverse auction where the validator would bid 4 coins. The difference is that the node is bonded within the epoch. The payment to get a validator seat is final. So if the validator does not perform, their admission fee is lost and they lose 6 coins. Thus, this auction format is the equivalent in DPoS of "slashing" a part of the bond.</p>
<p>The bond may seem low, but remember our thesis: We are only trying to keep honest actors from turning bad, and also not encourage careless operators with asymmetric risks.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The disadvantage of this model is that the blockchain must set the baseline reward wisely (10 coins in the above example). If the baseline is set very wrong, it can create an uncompetitive auction. We discuss this issue further below.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="thermostatic-baseline-price">Thermostatic Baseline Price<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#thermostatic-baseline-price" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Thermostatic Baseline Price" title="Direct link to Thermostatic Baseline Price">​</a></h3>
<p>How can the baseline price stay within a range in which the bidders are motivated to participate, given the external market conditions? If one sets the baseline too high and not enough biders show up, the network may dilute or exhaust their reward subsidies. If the baseline becomes too low, then no bidders show up.</p>
<p>Suppose the baseline reward to validators is set too low, given extrinsic market conditions. Such a situation does not create a large implicit bond, and thus does not create an effective deterrent. For example, suppose that instead of setting the baseline reward at 10 in the above example, the reward was set to 5. Now validators will bid up to 1 for the right to earn 5 but this means that a validator that fails to validate loses only 1. Worse yet if the baseline reward falls to less than 4 then eventually no validators show up. To solve for this, a “thermostatic” solution could be applied: as in home heating devices, the heat increases or decreases by a certain amount to target a given temperature.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Let’s look at an example. Let the baseline reward be BR and the cost of validation C then validators will bid up to BR-C to enter the validation set. To simplify notation we can assume that C contains an opportunity cost of capital so that if bidders are paid C they are earning a normal profit. In this case, in a competitive market, bids will rise until Bid=BR-C. (Recall from the previous example that BR was 10, C was 4 and bids rose to 6). The bid is also the equivalent bond since it is the bid which may be lost by failing to validate. Now from this perspective, there is an easy solution to setting the baseline reward: Set it absurdly high, say 1000. In this case bids will rise to 996 and validators will be extremely careful never to fail to validate since the bond is 996. The problem with this simple solution is that the higher the bond the greater the rewards to collusion and the more risk is imposed on validators. The competitive price in this scenario is 996 but even minimal collusion that brought the price down to say 900 would create very large profits and thus this model is asking for collusion. Even without collusion there may arise a situation where, for accidental or unusual reasons, there are only a handful of bidders who bid say 900 or less and thus they win the rights to earn 1000 for a pittance. In addition, a very high bid/bond means that an error on the part of the validators (“trembling hands”) subjects them to large losses. Risk aversion may then dissuade bidders from bidding which in turn could make collusion easier. High fees could thus potentially put the network at risk. Low fees, however, result in too few bidders as we noted above.</p>
<p>Thus, the protocol must target a bid (BR-C) which is large enough to promote good and careful behavior on the part of the validators but also small enough to not induce collusion and to withstand “trembling hands,” i.e. small errors in competitive behavior or execution. Fortunately, there is a very large range under which these conditions are satisfied. Thus, the targeting need not be precise.</p>
<p>Essentially we want the bid to be large enough so that poor performance hurts but not so large as to deter bidders for fear of losing the bond nor so large as to encourage collusion. It’s likely that a bond greater than 2C would be enough which would mean BR-C&gt;2C or BR&gt;3C and BR&gt;5C would be plenty so we would target a baseline reward (BR) at 3 to 5 times validator costs. Costs (including opportunity costs) don’t vary much over time so this could be set slowly.&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are a few ways this could be implemented. Some blockchains may find it acceptable to set this manually through governance (one or two times a year), though this just creates another issue to quarrel about. It's possible an oracle could be used to target an extrinsic price signal, i.e. the dollar price of the reward. Though we would prefer on-chain algorithms.</p>
<p>A simple algorithm could be implemented that when the bids are persistently near 100% or 0% of the reward then the baseline may increase or decrease by N coins in the following epoch. Alternatively, something more straightforward may be possible: Target BR so that the number of bidders relative to the validator set is always large and well above the validator set. That is, BR would rise as the number of bidders fell and fall as the number of bidders rose. Again, the precision does not matter, so long as BR doesn't fall out of range for a prolonged period of time.</p>
<p>Note again, that because the bidders will bid more when the BR rises there is little to no danger in a large BR so long as there are many bidders and we avoid situations where BR is so high that the network cannot afford accidental large payments.</p>
<p>The numbers, above, are illustrations. The actual numbers would need to be experimentally tested and paired with thermostatic adjustments to properly tune the design space.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="implementation-details">Implementation Details<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#implementation-details" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Implementation Details" title="Direct link to Implementation Details">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="limited-validator-set-rotation">Limited Validator Set Rotation<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#limited-validator-set-rotation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Limited Validator Set Rotation" title="Direct link to Limited Validator Set Rotation">​</a></h3>
<p>The auction should not be used to replace the entirety of the seats in the validator set. For example, if there are 21 seats available, and there are 100 candidates for the seats, it wouldn't be prudent to allow all the 21 seats to be replaced by highest bidders from the 100 candidates.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Theoretically, the problem here is that a sufficiently well funded adversary, with no experience (or perhaps even the hardware) could completely halt the network simply by creating accounts and funding them. While we think madmen scenarios are unlikely, this would just be an invitation to them.&nbsp;</p>
<p>As we discussed above, operator error is the most common threat, (ou may have ⅓ of the nodes that simply were not ready, or were hit by a data center outage, or failed to upgrade, or were asleep, etc.). This problem also exists in PoS blockchains, and the most common solution to this as observed in the field is to limit the validator rotation&nbsp;</p>
<p>In practice this means limiting the amount of turnover between one epoch and the next for exactly this reason. In PoF, we would have to accommodate for this as well. For example, no more than ⅓ of the new incoming validators can be of unknown "readiness". (Practically, it should be a lower number than one third to accommodate for 2f+1 errors where you might be putting your network really at the borderline of forming consensus. So perhaps ¼ is better.)</p>
<p>Fortunately the solution is straightforward for PoF: Rank the maximum bidders of outgoing and prospective sets, and drop the bottom ⅓ validators from outgoing set to open up for the prospects.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Assuming epoch E1 and E2, and a prospective validator universe P, which is a set of all bidding validator candidates, and the respective epoch validators V1 and V2. We first fill the two-thirds of cardinality of V2, i.e,&nbsp; ⅔ * V2, with <em>the</em> highest bids of V1, called continuing, denoted by C. Then we fill the set of (V2-C) with the ranked bids of P excluding C the continuing validators.&nbsp;</p>
<p>This way the union is always maximizing for the highest bidders, and not endangering the network for halts by operator unpreparedness.</p>
<p>Readers might ask, why not take the most reliable validators by some metric, and then auction off the remaining ⅓ of the seats? This leads to a couple problems:</p>
<ol>
<li>You're introducing a vector for gaming. A validator that is consistently the best performing will rationally bid zero. And as such this opens a Sybil issue and malicious behavior can be rewarded. Moreover, the auction is not maximizing revenue.</li>
<li>More importantly, we don't have reliable metrics to use on-chain for this. We only really know who signed and who proposed the previous block at any time. If we create a target threshold from either of these points, we introduce other undesirable properties of a network that should be plausibly neutral. In PBFT there's one artifact of networking which would cause the validators that are in the nearest datacenters (by network ping) to propagate their proposals and votes faster. Thus, to rely solely on the ratio of signatures or proposals creates a race to centralization.</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-seats-should-be-uniform">The Seats Should Be Uniform<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#the-seats-should-be-uniform" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Seats Should Be Uniform" title="Direct link to The Seats Should Be Uniform">​</a></h3>
<p>The product of the auction matters: Is it auctioning consensus power, or consensus seats of the same power?</p>
<p>The mechanism described above is notionally for multiple units of the same product: Seats in consensus. However, BFT consensus has another feature which is voting weights, or consensus power. Every block requires a quorum to be committed where quorum is two-thirds of total voting weight. A validator selection process needs to also address the weight of each vote in reaching consensus. In DPoS systems, stakers have their&nbsp; "consensus weight" determined by the amount staked. The implication of a higher consensus weight is that the nodes are able to cast more "votes" on a block, and thus have an outsized role in consensus. Layered on top of that may be an economic reward for proposers (for example, the proposer bonus in Cosmos Hub).</p>
<p>In having different weights, especially when there is huge deviation, consensus would be reached faster by reaching a quorum with lesser participants. For instance, some PoS networks have 100+ validators but only the top 5 make the quorum.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Our current opinion is that all seats should be treated equally. Most BFT academic work, and deployment pre-blockchain, assume equal weights. Recent derivations, such as HotStuff, Narwhal, and BlockSTM, talk in terms of equal weight in their published academic work. It was with Tendermint and DPoS that the concept of weighting gained prominence (possibly because of an assumption that it would optimize the auction for seats by stake, which may not bear out).</p>
<p>We think that variable votes in consensus removes one of the important sybil resistance properties of the "madman" attack described above. That said there may be a reason a blockchain wishes to give greater weight to different nodes.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Through entry fees, a node could be assigned relative weights depending on the price that they bid. That is, the nodes which forgo the most payment will have higher chances of qualifying for liveness. Conversely, the nodes whose hardware and operation constantly perform the highest, will likely be able to charge higher fees, since they are not at risk of being below threshold. Auctioning a “liveness bonus”, so to speak, is a price signal, and there may be legitimate reasons why validators are needing to get a bonus (their nodes are harder to reach).&nbsp;</p>
<p>Future research should decide if there is a meaningful optimization in having variable votes per seat, without compromising the security. Note variable votes per seat has important consequences for the auction mechanism (more detail below).</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="auction-formats">Auction Formats<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#auction-formats" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Auction Formats" title="Direct link to Auction Formats">​</a></h3>
<p>There are multiple auction formats that should be discussed. There's a risk in getting side-tracked in a discussion on auction mechanisms, but fundamentally, the big picture is simple: There's no auction mechanism that can correct for the absence of bidders. Ensuring an ample supply of bidders that always exceeds the number of validator slots is of first order importance.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The auctioneer maximizes revenue mainly by having better products. And if the product can’t be improved, the auction increases revenue by adding another&nbsp; marginal bidder. This needs to be highlighted: <strong>Everyone’s effort is best spent on making a better product</strong>. The only job of the auction designer is to eliminate the worst auctions, and then pick the auction that is easiest to understand by the bidder, and appears fair. This will increase the amount of bidders, and thus revenue.</p>
<p>In terms of picking the auction, the designer needs to&nbsp; prioritize certain features, as these decisions will impact your choice of auction format and configuration. Key issues impacting that choice are:&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>Whether to optimize for revenue of the chain?</li>
<li>Should validators bid their true expected utility?</li>
<li>Are seats uniform?</li>
<li>What level of privacy is desired?</li>
<li>Do we expect collusion from bidders?</li>
</ul>
<p>The principal decision to be made is whether the product is "votes" in consensus or seats which are all equal. Above, we recommend seats with the same consensus weight, but we will give some notes below for the auction for votes scenario.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="if-all-seats-are-equal"><em>If All Seats Are Equal</em><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#if-all-seats-are-equal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to if-all-seats-are-equal" title="Direct link to if-all-seats-are-equal">​</a></h4>
<p>The most important optimization as we say above is that the auction has to invite the most bidders, that is: It needs to be low friction, not require much analysis, and generally feel fair.</p>
<h5 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="vickrey-clarke-groves">Vickrey-Clarke-Groves<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#vickrey-clarke-groves" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Vickrey-Clarke-Groves" title="Direct link to Vickrey-Clarke-Groves">​</a></h5>
<p>The main constraint on the auction design is whether private bidding is possible. A sealed bid, (implemented with commit-reveal) may be possible, but is likely impractical for the workflows of operators. Assuming this was an acceptable position, we could make use of incentive-compatible Vickrey-Clarke-Groves auctions. There's a lot to be said about VCG auctions and their ability to surface bidder preferences in a truthful manner. In blockchain applications, however, this has been impractical, so we need to consider open auction formats.</p>
<h5 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="open-nth-price-auctions">Open Nth-Price Auctions<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#open-nth-price-auctions" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Open Nth-Price Auctions" title="Direct link to Open Nth-Price Auctions">​</a></h5>
<p>The simplest and most common auction type is a <em>first price auction</em>. Despite known tradeoffs Blockchains implement first prices often, and they seem reliable in adversarial environments. First price auctions can be conducted in the open. Bitcoin uses first price for transaction ordering. A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generalized_first-price_auction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Generalized First Price Auction</a> has been historically used in online environments (ads), also for positional ordering, but it is difficult for bidders to discover optimal strategies and for these reasons is susceptible to manipulation (reducing revenue to auctioneer) based on its non-truthful properties.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generalized_second-price_auction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Generalized Second Price Auction</a> (also a variation of a Vickrey Auction), seems similar to a Vickrey auction but is misnamed since the truthful properties of bidding are not always preserved in GSP. (VCG is the true generalized second price auction.) For similar reasons, the bidder has to work on figuring out where they are placed with other validators. In practice, it works reasonably well, however, and revenues are typically as high as in VCG.</p>
<h5 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="uniform-price-auctions">Uniform price auctions<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#uniform-price-auctions" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Uniform price auctions" title="Direct link to Uniform price auctions">​</a></h5>
<p>We recommend a single price auction for the case of uniform seats. (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single-price_auction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Also called treasury auctions,</a> since this format is used in U.S. Treasury market operations.) The last ranked qualifying bid sets the price for all validators.</p>
<p>This may be counter intuitive, but even though everyone pays the <em>lowest</em> accepted bid the revenue to the auctioneer has been demonstrated to be similar to other auction formats such as the first price format in which everyone pays their own bid. In essence, under first price people shade their bids down but in a uniform auction bids are higher and it works out that on average revenues are the same. The major advantage of uniform-price auctions is that it's easier for the bidders to know what to do: They can bid their true preferences since they will never overpay. Gaming may not be worth the effort. It's an elegant solution, and very easily applied to blockchain contexts, though it would require that all seats have the same properties.</p>
<p>Uniform price auctions are usually done as a sealed-bid, however it appears that open auctions with repeat bidding, with bids that cannot be retracted (lowered), will approximate the revenue of sealed bids. A reserve price also helps prevent non-truthful bidding.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="if-selling-votes-in-consensus"><em>If Selling Votes in Consensus</em><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#if-selling-votes-in-consensus" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to if-selling-votes-in-consensus" title="Direct link to if-selling-votes-in-consensus">​</a></h4>
<p>In the case of auctioning variable votes in consensus we have multiple units of the product, and the bidder can buy multiple ones. Typically a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiunit_auction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">sealed multiunit auction</a> would be recommended. Though we have the same privacy issues described above for VCG. The multi-unit auction and single price auctions have a winner take all problem, where one bidder can take all the votes available in consensus in a single bid: if you know the highest price you can outbid and take all&nbsp; votes available.</p>
<p>Given these issues we should consider nth-price auctions. A generalized first price auction (described above) would be the alternative to experiment with. This format gives the bidder the value that they were willing to pay. It is also practical for blockchain environments and can be played openly, but not perfectly susceptible to collusion with a limited amount of bidders.&nbsp; If they were to pay a lower price than what they bid (as in a second price auction), the incentive is to vote only above the remaining votes, possibly shading the bid.&nbsp;</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="negative-fees">Negative Fees<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#negative-fees" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Negative Fees" title="Direct link to Negative Fees">​</a></h3>
<p>Negative fees are possible, and might be allowed in PoF since they are a relevant price signal. As described above, if bidders are consistently on average bidding 100% of the reward, this means that the reward is low, and we might be losing validators because we are not paying the opportunity cost. If 100% was the limit, it would be hard to discover how much we are underpaying. That is, it might take longer for a thermostatic mechanism to adjust. Said differently: Thermostatic baseline pricing allows for negative fee price signaling.</p>
<p>Negative fees should be avoided if there is no thermostatic adjustment, due to the risk of making validators compete on MEV frontrunning. Validators may engage in frontrunning, and as such should pay for it – PoF allows for this. It becomes something of a detractor for those who try to gain an edge with MEV.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In another situation, it’s conceivable that MEV might become widespread, and negative fees would force validators who are not engaging in front running to do so in order to remain competitive. PoF is not a solution to MEV; this will eventually be resolved through engineering advances in transaction inclusion design (e.g. proposer and validator separation). Until this gets solved, the blockchain can monetize some of the MEV.</p>
<p>If negative fees are permitted, there must be lower bounds, even though negative fees means more revenue for coin holders until the thermostatic adjustment kicks in. Without limits, it would be trivial for a sufficiently funded Byzantine adversary to take all the seats (or consensus power depending on auction) in a given epoch.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="discussion">Discussion<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#discussion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Discussion" title="Direct link to Discussion">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ergonomics">Ergonomics<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#ergonomics" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Ergonomics" title="Direct link to Ergonomics">​</a></h3>
<p>The greatest benefit of PoF is that it is simple. Every actor has a very simple instruction on what to do:</p>
<ul>
<li>Holders: Just hold. You are losing nothing by being passive.</li>
<li>Validators: Bid what it's worth to you.</li>
<li>Apps: Developers can develop scenarios where the coin is used in the app, or held, without risking its loss of value from dilution.</li>
</ul>
<p>There are no secret handshakes, it doesn't require being able to become connected to capital to fund your stake. Historical DPoS networks have started by using a company or foundation sponsoring the initial stakes of validators (and this is often hidden information). PoF removes this out-of-band game. It not only provides an open opportunity to prospective validators, it's optimal for the network: The validators must compete on price, and not pre-existing business relationships.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="bonding">Bonding<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#bonding" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Bonding" title="Direct link to Bonding">​</a></h3>
<p>The greatest question about PoF is if it is safe. Put differently, is the inter-epoch bond (the entry fee) a sufficient deterrent.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In DPOS systems, very large bonds are placed to disincentivize, via the cost of capital of the parked coins combined with the threat of slashing. These costs appear to work. But to what extent is the cost too high? The bond and expense of a validator in DPOS is measured in the collateral and the expense of the cost of capital during the epoch. This cost can be orders of magnitude greater than the profit of the validator during the epoch.</p>
<p>The trap is that, in DPOS, the answer to the question of how much of a bond is needed is usually "more". Modeling this is an exercise fraught with assumptions. Above we argue that the baseline "'honesty assumptions" of BFT and the empirical evidence show that slashing large stakes is not needed. Notably, Avalanche blockchain is a Proof-of-Stake network without slashing.</p>
<p>PoF has no slashing except for losing the bid, which is effectively a bond. The question PoF asks is whether that bond needs to be 1,000X the profit, or if by slashing smaller stakes (i.e. the bid) repeatedly, if need be, we will have the same deterrence on less-than-competent validators.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="delegation">Delegation<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#delegation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Delegation" title="Direct link to Delegation">​</a></h3>
<p>A notable feature of Proof of Fee is that there is no delegation. Delegation in POS proposes to solve two issues: (1) how to distribute rewards broadly, and (2) how to have economic agents participate in validator selection.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="less-investor-rent-seeking"><em>Less investor rent-seeking</em><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#less-investor-rent-seeking" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to less-investor-rent-seeking" title="Direct link to less-investor-rent-seeking">​</a></h4>
<p>We assume with DPOS that all rewards are distributed to the "stakers" of the validator, and that a marginal fee (usually around 3-5%) is paid to the validator's operator. Historically, this means the initial stakes are set up by investors from conventional venture capital or, until about 2019, "retail" market ICOs. As we stated earlier, there are social effects to having this investor class receiving rents from future depositors.</p>
<p>In PoF, the principal property is that all coin holders are effectively stakers of the entire validator set. This is because PoF removes delegation and the investor class. While there are opportunities for capitalists in PoF, such as financing entry fees, this operates much more like a type of receivables financing rather than a preferred shares early investor financing. There could be no broader distribution of excess rewards. So, while PoF welcomes capitalist financing, it does not depend on it to get off the ground, and doesn't promise rents into perpetuity above and beyond what other coin holders receive.&nbsp;</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="participation-in-validator-selection"><em>Participation in Validator Selection</em><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#participation-in-validator-selection" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to participation-in-validator-selection" title="Direct link to participation-in-validator-selection">​</a></h4>
<p>Validator selection is an issue on PBFT chains. PoF and DPOS have similar issues when there is no mechanism for selecting validators beyond economics, i.e. the party with the most economic budget can join the validator set.</p>
<p>A PBFT network is born from a group of validators, and the social norms of those validators propagate to subsequent participants. In contrast, PoF leaves the question of validator selection open, allowing for variations of delegation to exist, for example:</p>
<ul>
<li>On-chain or off-chain vouching mechanisms for validators will be desired by most communities.</li>
<li>Delegation, whereby validators may receive loans from different agents to pay for entry fees.</li>
<li>A community may even be willing to risk adversarial nodes (e.g. MEV) in consensus for a while. We would expect that such behavior would quickly cease to be attractive as participants are outbid by honest agents.</li>
</ul>
<p>The DPOS hypothesis is that the holders of coins are good estimators of validator "quality" for the network. This is actually a public goods provision problem: A free rider problem. Estimating the abilities and usefulness of a validator is valuable to the network, but someone must pay for it, and neither end-user nor validator has the incentive to pay to create that information.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The DPOS hypothesis is that staking is a good heuristic. The trouble is that the game forces operators to have a distributed group of economic agents wager on which validator they should be a party to. Empirically, this leads to a race from operators to offer "rebates" and negative commissions to users. Additionally, in practice, many stakers are in fact passive and allow their virtual asset service provider (i.e. Coinbase, Binance, etc.) to choose the destination of the delegation (usually their own nodes). On the part of the account holder, this is a perfectly rational decision in response to asymmetric information about the blockchain's condition. It's not entirely obvious that there is a high signal from the stakers on validator selection. Do we really know if we are picking the best, most performant and honest validator set? There are commentators in the field that say that the opposite often happens.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="delegation-increases-costs"><em>Delegation increases Costs</em><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#delegation-increases-costs" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to delegation-increases-costs" title="Direct link to delegation-increases-costs">​</a></h4>
<p>Our hypothesis is that the cost of consensus is not only higher on non-staked depositors in DPOS, but also it is higher globally. That is, for the transaction fees of the chain to adequately cover the security budget of consensus, the fees need to be sufficient to cover the opportunity costs of not only the operator, but also of the stakers.&nbsp;</p>
<p>This means that higher transaction fees are needed than in the absence of delegation, and this picture is further complicated when issuance is needed to supplant that deficit in transaction fees. Non-staked coin holders are disadvantaged by this design.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="law">Law<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#law" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Law" title="Direct link to Law">​</a></h3>
<p>A final point to mention here is regulatory profile. This topic is of increasing relevance to actors in this sector and DPoS needs to be considered in light of what is known. There's a long discussion to be had on whether regulatory issues are outside of protocol or not, that is, should regulators be considered agents in your game and is regulation an attack vector. Regardless of your views on that, DPoS clearly has a heightened regulatory profile due to the presence of various approaches to pooling, lending, and equity that variations of DPoS apply. Proof of Fee and its cost to enter the service market is more distinct, in that it does not rely on overt capital pooling mechanisms.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-2#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>The PoF design is upside-down from mainstream blockchains: Usually the protocol determines the price that is right for each validator, and the validator can choose to enter the validator set. As such it needs to make assumptions about private information of the validator, and so the validator is left with a binary choice: Take it or leave it. Over the very long term this may approximate opportunity cost, but with the practice of most blockchains heavily weighting rewards to early participants, the blockchain usually errs on the side of overpaying for security. In PoF, the onus is on the validator to reveal the correct price of consensus.</p>
<p>The above proposal starts with the assumption that PBFT networks are theoretically resilient before economic guarantees are applied: They a) have a high bar for transaction reordering which is easily caught with cryptography, and b) walk a trusted graph of nodes from the genesis. As such those chains have a higher safety profile than Nakamoto consensus for many theoretical threats. As for economic guarantees, DPOS on PBFT is cheaper than PoW with Nakamoto consensus.</p>
<p>With PoF we may be able to make PBFT even more cost effective for the chain, by safely removing delegation, which adds costs and taxes the less-informed and the accounts that are otherwise restricted from staking. If anything, our conclusion is that DPoS may be a local maximum, and there is still further experimentation to be made on economic guarantees for PBFT consensus.</p>
<p>Proof of Fee, with its emphasis on reducing the cost of security to a market-driven minimum, provides a new mechanism for blockchains concerned with building sustainable business models and for those concerned with maintaining greater equity among the participants in their ecosystem. We think this is a first step to creating networks that the mainstream population actually want to belong to.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>PoF</category>
            <category>Proof of Fee</category>
            <category>canonical</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proof of Fee - Part 1]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Cost of Consensus]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-cost-of-consensus">The Cost of Consensus<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#the-cost-of-consensus" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Cost of Consensus" title="Direct link to The Cost of Consensus">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="tldr">TL;DR<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#tldr" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to TL;DR" title="Direct link to TL;DR">​</a></h3>
<p>As an alternative to the (near-universally deployed) Delegated Proof of Stake (DPoS), we propose Proof of Fee (PoF), a sybil resistance technique designed natively and with consideration of the benefits and tradeoffs of PBFT consensus from empirical experience.</p>
<ul>
<li>Profits to blockchains are slim to non-existent. Low consensus costs are foundational for any chain that wishes to provide consumer surplus and profit to coin-holders; where excess winnings of the chain can be distributed to <em>all</em> account holders without preference to an investor class of "stakers".</li>
<li>In PoF the cost of consensus is lowered maximally to the <em>operator opportunity cost</em>; with such an approach, the social cost of dilution through issuance is minimized.</li>
<li>Validator seats are auctioned at each epoch, such that the validators private valuation of rewards, MEV, breakage, and governance is revealed.</li>
<li>PoF coins have superior ergonomics. Every actor has a very simple instruction; no staking, no delegation, no yield games, no slashing.</li>
</ul>
<div class="codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar" style="color:#393A34;background-color:#f6f8fa"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">Before we dive into the mechanics of Proof-of-Fee, in Part 1 of this paper we lay some foundations which may be different from what you have seen elsewhere. [Part 2 of the paper](http://openlibra.blog/2022/10/20/proof-of-fee-part-2-a-proposal/) gets into the mechanics and implementation details of Proof-of-Fee (PoF), an affordable sybil resistance technique native to PBFT consensus.</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-not-delegated-proof-of-stake">Why Not Delegated Proof of Stake?<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#why-not-delegated-proof-of-stake" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Why Not Delegated Proof of Stake?" title="Direct link to Why Not Delegated Proof of Stake?">​</a></h2>
<p>While the purpose of the document is not to dissect DPoS, what follows&nbsp; is the briefest context&nbsp; on reasons why DPoS may not work for a blockchain's community.&nbsp;</p>
<p>A meaningful issue is the "ergonomics" of the token, that is, how do humans interact with it. End users may be unsophisticated and not know how to stake. They may have coins on an exchange which does not offer staking services. The coins may be in escrow in an application's smart contract, or across a bridge. Some of these issues are surmountable if there were sufficient education and infrastructure, but in the meantime the result is a disparity between the percentage of tokens staked and the percentage of account holders. A large percentage of the token supply may be staked (by whales and the savvy coin holders), but it represents only a small number of the total wallets.</p>
<p>Modern DPoS blockchains are also universally deployed with "inflation" or issuance of new coins to subsidize the validator operators and their stakers. This may be necessary because transaction fees from producing blocks are far lower than the validators deem acceptable to provide their services.</p>
<p>The result is that the accounts which are not staking are effectively paying a fee to the stakers. This means usually the retail investors are paying a fee to keep an account on the chain (a wealth tax) often to the founding members of the chain (venture capitalists and developers). This is not a widely advertised property of such chains.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Promoters of the chains may say that this is transitory, that transaction fees will one day catch up, but this should be viewed with some skepticism. Looking forward to the next ten years, the cost of each state transition on a blockchain will drop radically due to secular engineering advances (e.g., parallelization, mempool optimization, sharding, layer 2, etc.); given a trend towards commoditization, prices tend to drop to marginal levels. Given the likelihood of a paucity of revenue from transaction fees, DPoS blockchains may be structurally and permanently in the business of taxing the depositors.</p>
<p>There is also some debate around the "delegation" component of DPOS and whether it is serving its purpose. Delegation is expensive as it adds to the cost of consensus (because now there are more people, and more opportunity costs, that need to be compensated). The cost must achieve the goals of plausible neutrality (decentralization) and select for ideal validators. Instead, the empirical evidence of what delegation does is select for the parties that can accumulate capital (e.g. large centralized exchanges). That behavior does not necessarily align with achieving the goals.</p>
<p>Lastly, the staking requirements may be excessive, inefficient uses of capital. One should ask the question: Does the bond really need to be 1,000 to 1,000,000 times the reward of an epoch? Given that L1s have not empirically seen slashing of large stakes from malicious attacks, the level of bonding is disproportionate to the need (more below on nothing-at-stake issues).</p>
<p>We start from the assumption that more exploration needs to be done on economic guarantees for modern blockchains, which are mostly all based on PBFT and derivations thereof. Proof of Fee is proposed as an experiment.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="validator-economics">Validator Economics<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#validator-economics" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Validator Economics" title="Direct link to Validator Economics">​</a></h2>
<p>Since validators are the largest cost of a network, we need to clearly understand their costs and their expected utility from participating in a network.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Validators have a private valuation (<em>expected utility</em>) of a seat in consensus. The same validator has a private opportunity cost for the work it provides. If the expected utility is greater than the total costs, including opportunity cost, then a rational validator should participate in consensus.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="validator-costs">Validator Costs<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#validator-costs" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Validator Costs" title="Direct link to Validator Costs">​</a></h3>
<p>One of the roles of protocol engineers is to lower the hard costs associated with being a validator; make the tools work reliably, make the node software use less hardware resources, and provide greater automation and monitoring.</p>
<p>Technical matters, however, cannot address all of the costs of the validator; there are also opportunity costs. The time it takes for the staff to operate the nodes, research, participate in governance, and do business administration could be used for other purposes (on other chains). Additionally, if there is a financial cost such as staking, then that value could always be used elsewhere, staked elsewhere.</p>
<p>Opportunity cost is out of the control of protocol engineers and designers, it is a feature of the global markets (labor, tokens, compute, energy, etc.).</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="validator-utility">Validator Utility<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#validator-utility" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Validator Utility" title="Direct link to Validator Utility">​</a></h3>
<p>Given that the opportunity cost is extrinsic, profitability for the validator (and the blockchain) is created by the business environment of the blockchain. Some of the factors that contribute to the private assessment of the utility of the validator seat are tangible and easily measurable (transaction fees), others are intangible and highly subjective (governance roles).</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="transaction-fees"><em>Transaction Fees</em><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#transaction-fees" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to transaction-fees" title="Direct link to transaction-fees">​</a></h4>
<p>Most blockchains describe transaction fees as a title (property right) of node operators. (Note in Proof of Fee we take the view that transaction fees are a title of the coin holders, more on that later). The transaction fees flow by default to network operators. Most often those fees are far lower than what those same validators are earning from network subsidies.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="subsidies"><em>Subsidies</em><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#subsidies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to subsidies" title="Direct link to subsidies">​</a></h4>
<p>Most blockchains provide subsidies in addition to transaction fees. This is supposed to supplement the validator's earnings while bootstrapping the network and the transactions are insufficient. Even in 2022 the most established blockchain, Bitcoin, generated only a fraction of earnings from transaction fees: Roughly 1% (i.e., roughly 99% comes from subsidies - see the chart, below).</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/IDSFhHIiMq_FQMvE7JKvK9tlUD9pKIRvXl-XJ_aDk5U2bur44IjQAQLx41gfWYUn6xOKHTKMkrR1Y2x--7UguUH0L-WlUJhpiW92PRzTEda8Ix8_uo_4HWSU3vsP1zMUl-IsbKcAR4LpyuihYRg6mN5pkX-gkBzwWr3OiJmDqXBcAlm5kYsc5kTu" alt="" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Source: <a href="https://www.theblock.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TheBlock.co</a></p>
<p>As a matter of practice, subsidies are almost exclusively newly issued network equity, and as such are dilutive. Meaning, subsidies are a cost to depositors on a blockchain due to the reduction in their percent equity. Assuming a network with a constant market-cap valuation (which we must do from a unit-economics analysis), new issuance to the miner which produced security, is a reduction in value to anyone who didn't receive a new coin. Additionally, this new equity is financing the current security needs by time shifting future earnings from transaction fees (presumably, unless new revenue models are discovered).</p>
<p>All known blockchains are loss-making in this regard. While Ethereum makes some claims about becoming profitable, it remains to be seen whether this can be sustained over more than a brief period (, and there are at least a few pundits out there who are questioning that claim).&nbsp;</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="no-show-rewards"><em>No-Show Rewards</em><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#no-show-rewards" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to no-show-rewards" title="Direct link to no-show-rewards">​</a></h4>
<p>Another aspect of validator utility to consider is no-shows from other validators, that is, drop-outs from competitors. When a validator is successful in the validator set, and one or more of its peers fails in consensus, there is a surplus of transaction fees (or subsidies) that are available to it. Meaning, the pool of rewards within an epoch is greater than what was nominally attributable to the validator at the start of the epoch. We separate this from the topic above because chance is involved and part of the utility is a wager on the success of the peers.</p>
<p>This is relevant because even if validation is nominally not profitable from transaction fees or expected subsidies, the validator may see value in "staying in the game" in case another node falls out.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="mev"><em>MEV</em><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#mev" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to mev" title="Direct link to mev">​</a></h4>
<p>MEV is a category of earnings that a validator can create by engaging in different types of frontrunning as it prepares transactions into blocks. As of 2022, this has become an important source of revenue for many operators.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Though MEV seems to be becoming acceptable in some circles, when viewed through another lens, it can be argued that engaging in MEV violates the spirit of the agreement between validators and users. Validators are employing their access to insider information to game the system. From that perspective, MEV is an attack on the integrity of the system. (You can view a compilation of MEV attacks documented at <a href="https://www.mev.wiki/attack-examples" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.mev.wiki/attack-examples</a>.)</p>
<p>From 2021 to 2022, the tools for engaging in MEV attacks have become commoditized on Ethereum, and the cumulative costs approach $700M taken from users.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/J6P-cUzicXGsCa6TyeCe8YmYykkYsOKnZpB5EQ1G6IvbG-rWc-b1JE98Blvhfz1yHsdA02I19Y34R8xSib4v1JKFNcqnPI42hgi5tqXFLY-9n2fFe7N6ZafPT4f-6-DUUByYx4D3tGR0UYn_SYhoX61inTYU8zl02joNeunR5oDsBq5N-3oZIKPJ" alt="" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Source: <a href="https://explore.flashbots.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://explore.flashbots.net/</a></p>
<p>MEV can be significant. In the early days of the Ethereum Post-Merge, as the cost of consensus went down, the share of MEV became higher. In September 2022, post merge, the MEV would average $100K, per day, while earnings from subsidies was $2M and transaction fees roughly $700k. Though on certain days, there are worrisome outliers, on September 27th 2022, the total subsidies paid to operators was $2.14M, while Tx Fees was $0.67M and the MEV was $1.5 M, that is 50% extra earnings over expected in-protocol earnings. (see, <a href="https://www.theblock.co/data/on-chain-metrics/ethereum" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.theblock.co/data/on-chain-metrics/ethereum</a>).&nbsp;</p>
<p>In the long term there may be technical solutions to MEV attacks, such as the block producer and proposer separation seen in Ethereum (Flashbots MEV-Boost Relay). There may also be solutions on the application layer for "tricking the bots" (see: <a href="https://www.mev.wiki/attempts-to-trick-the-bots" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.mev.wiki/attempts-to-trick-the-bots</a>), and for fun see some applications' mousetraps: (<a href="https://www.coindesk.com/tech/2021/03/22/bad-sandwich-defi-trader-poisons-front-running-miners-for-250k-profit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.coindesk.com/tech/2021/03/22/bad-sandwich-defi-trader-poisons-front-running-miners-for-250k-profit/</a>)</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="governance"><em>Governance</em><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#governance" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to governance" title="Direct link to governance">​</a></h4>
<p>Validator utility also includes the exercise of governance rights. Validators have outsized roles in governance (parameter changes, state machine upgrades). In fact, it may be said that validators hold the only "hard power" governance. Validators can always coordinate to apply a write to the database and that control over the protocol gives them de facto power to set policy. Most chains try to apply lower friction ways of other stakeholders changing policy, however ultimately the validator has the last say (or veto) on policies. Even if there are other governance mechanisms on-chain, validators may in collusion reject such transactions which trigger an upgrade (more below on types of malicious behavior). Resolving this balance of power is not the topic of this paper; suffice to say that the validator can reasonably have a private valuation for this governance role.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="cost-of-consensus">Cost of Consensus<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#cost-of-consensus" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Cost of Consensus" title="Direct link to Cost of Consensus">​</a></h2>
<p>Consensus is a shorthand for getting a database transaction approved, though there is some confusion in equating a consensus algorithm, and a sybil resistance mechanism. Usually when we refer to cost of consensus we mean both inputs. Proof of stake was an evolution in reducing the cost of preventing sybil attacks, in both reducing the hardware costs in preventing attacks from malicious actors.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="pow-sybil-resistance">PoW Sybil resistance<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#pow-sybil-resistance" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to PoW Sybil resistance" title="Direct link to PoW Sybil resistance">​</a></h3>
<p>Nakomoto consensus (invented for Bitcoin) relies on the longest chain principle, but it depends on Proof of Work (PoW) for sybil resistance. The longest chain principle helps in sequencing blocks of transactions, but not just anyone is allowed to do that. PoW as an identity mechanism says the block is proposed by the largest pool of CPU power. The more the CPU power of a pool, the more likely they get to propose the next block and hence, better rewards. As long as most CPU power rests with honest nodes, they outpace Byzantine actors by proposing more blocks.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Over time, the demands for computing power kept rising from CPUs to GPUs to ASICs. As a result, the capital for infrastructure and the recurring cost of electricity resources kept growing, leading to increased costs for consensus (besides energy we have cost of capital).&nbsp;</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-pos-solves-and-the-nothing-at-stake-problem">What PoS solves and the Nothing-at-stake problem<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#what-pos-solves-and-the-nothing-at-stake-problem" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What PoS solves and the Nothing-at-stake problem" title="Direct link to What PoS solves and the Nothing-at-stake problem">​</a></h3>
<p>Proof of Stake (PoS) addresses Sybil attacks using native tokens as a stake in the system in place of the capital requirements of the hardware. This approach significantly lowers the cost of sybil attack behavior compared to Nakomoto consensus plus PoW due to a drop in the cost of computation (since no proof of work puzzles need to be solved).&nbsp;</p>
<p>However, this reduced cost could lead to nothing at stake problem wherein validators could behave arbitrarily (see, <a href="https://blog.ethereum.org/2014/07/05/stake" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vitalik's original</a> description of the nothing at stake problem). In short: It's cheap for validators to create forks of the network, for example in a long range attack creating many plausible forks that in the future may be presented at the canonical fork. And for this reason, the earliest DPoS chains implemented high deposits and "slashing" when double-signing was occurring. As we will see later, there has been debate as to whether the threat of the penalty has any effect, or if the value of the bond is actually the cost-of-capital of the parked coins, thus negating that there is really a nothing-at-stake issue.</p>
<p>DPoS can be applied to numerous consensus algorithms (including Nakamoto, though not plausibly). The most well known is Tendermint PBFT implementations (or derivatives of Cosmos Hub), but there are many others in the wild.</p>
<p>Our concern is narrower: How economic guarantees interacts specifically with PBFT and its derivatives.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="profitability">Profitability<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#profitability" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Profitability" title="Direct link to Profitability">​</a></h3>
<p>If a network is profitable it will return value to coin holders. For this to happen, the revenue of the blockchain's products must be greater than the costs. That is, there can be no issuance of coins to fill the gap between what end-users paid for services, and the different costs of goods sold (the validators). As of 2022, there has never been a reliably profitable blockchain.</p>
<p>Currently the infrastructure costs of most blockchains are equal to the cost of consensus (i.e, only nodes and miners are paid).&nbsp; The true cost of consensus, as noted above, is not really technical or resource bound on post PoW chains; it’s the sum of the opportunity cost of validators. Validators have other means of using their time and compute resources to make money. Assuming a security guarantee of <em>S</em>, the validators have a cumulative opportunity cost of <em>C</em> (we don't assume these to be equal, or even necessarily correlated).</p>
<p>During bootstrapping of a network the relation between opportunity cost and issuance is indeterminate, since the network is discovering its value. In <strong>steady state</strong> however, the costs to the network should be the lowest possible (approaching the opportunity cost of node operators), such that the costs can be more readily covered with revenue. If the revenue cannot cover the cost of security, historically, chains have covered the shortfall by charging fees to account holders; those fees come in the form of dilution through issuance. Put another way, they pass through the costs to the account holders.</p>
<p>Chains can only provide security if the opportunity cost of a sufficiently non-colluding validator set is being met. Chains can only cover those costs if they are solvent (they have revenue). The chains can finance the deficit with issuance, but this is also a tangle since it can only have value if it is long-term solvent (by eventually having revenues greater or equal to security costs). Another way to think about it: Issuance is financing; it is only shifting the future revenues to the present validators.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="pbft-further-lowers-the-cost-of-consensus">PBFT Further Lowers the Cost of Consensus<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#pbft-further-lowers-the-cost-of-consensus" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to PBFT Further Lowers the Cost of Consensus" title="Direct link to PBFT Further Lowers the Cost of Consensus">​</a></h3>
<p>Proof of Stake is the dominant method of sybil resistance for PBFT chains. Proof of stake designs, however, predate implementation of PBFT consensus. The specifics of PBFT chains allow for different economic guarantees but, for historical reasons, those have not been fully explored. Moreover, there are some misunderstandings about the total security guarantee of PBFT chains in relation to economic costs.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="background-on-pbft">Background on PBFT<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#background-on-pbft" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Background on PBFT" title="Direct link to Background on PBFT">​</a></h3>
<p>The Byzantine Generals problem was posed four decades ago in 1982. The problem it addressed was how to reach a consensus among participants who might not necessarily trust each other and could have Byzantine failures. Reaching consensus facilitates state machine replication among distributed systems, where Byzantine failure is any arbitrary behavior, including intentional and unintentional behavior such as crash failures, collusion among participants, and software bugs. A solution to this problem is Byzantine fault-tolerant (BFT) consensus algorithms, a family of consensus protocols for distributed systems that provide both safety (“bad things don’t happen”) and liveness (“good things do happen”) guarantees.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The early BFT protocols assumed synchrony (i.e., synchronized clocks); that expectation can be challenging to obtain practically on the internet. PBFT is the first prominent practical solution to the Byzantine Generals problem. PBFT found its application in safety-critical systems, such as aircraft and submarines, where hardware is complex and may become unreliable in unpredictable ways, sometimes in hostile environments. Over the past two decades, we observed numerous advances to PBFT protocols with advances in networking and cryptography. These advances have significantly improved performance, measured throughput (tx/sec), and latencies.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Blockchains, where trust and security are critical, can leverage the underlying correctness guarantees of PBFT protocols. One downside, however, is that PBFT protocols assume a committee of participants and therefore can face Sybil attacks where a single participant has created multiple identities. To address this challenge, mechanism designs for establishing identity and economic incentives with guarantees from game theory are often necessary. One such mechanism widely used in blockchains is Proof of Stake, wherein anyone with native tokens in the system stakes their assets to become participants in the network. We've pointed out some of the issues with this sybil resistance approach, above.</p>
<p>History won't end with PBFT, there may be other consensus innovations in the future. For our purposes we assume that the technical cost of consensus (CPU, networking, disk) is a domain of computer science and that the lowest hanging fruit has already been plucked, absent a major breakthrough in the Byzantine Generals Problem.&nbsp;</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="walking-the-graph-the-disconnect-between-security-and-cost">Walking the graph: The Disconnect Between Security and Cost<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proof-of-fee-part-1#walking-the-graph-the-disconnect-between-security-and-cost" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Walking the graph: The Disconnect Between Security and Cost" title="Direct link to Walking the graph: The Disconnect Between Security and Cost">​</a></h3>
<p>Let us consider the common threat scenarios, relative to PBFT:</p>
<ol>
<li>Malicious transactions : Impossible unless signed by the user. One cannot append malicious transactions even if they have a majority. State machine replication would not let this happen and is guaranteed by cryptography.</li>
<li>Reverse/delete blocks after finality: Leads to another fork, means abandoning the current chain. For that fork to continue it requires a&nbsp; 2/3rd majority on each block of the new fork.</li>
<li>Malicious writes: Requires 2/3rd of nodes to approve a forced malicious write. This also requires coordinated action among the malicious validators and cannot happen with state machine replication.</li>
</ol>
<p>Empirically from approximately four years of PBFT permissionless networks in the wild, there is scant evidence of malicious writes to a database. One possible explanation for this may be the fact that chains are built by "walking" from a trusted root. All known blockchains using PBFT require starting up from a "genesis set". And usually this involves participating in a community (usually a company) and developing offline reputation. In few such networks are the validators anonymous.</p>
<p>Moreover, in PBFT there are games outside of consensus that increase the cost to authenticate (create reputation), such that amplification of attacks from performant malicious nodes becomes more costly. Systems can add other costs which then work in concert to create unsustainable costs for the attacker. There are a broad range of experiments in this area related to reputation, validator set accession, and disincentives for malicious behavior.</p>
<p>Mitigating attacks is not obviously mapped to economic costs. And economic costs will not exclusively deal with those attacks. Any analysis of cost paid for security versus the estimated dollar value of a safe transaction to send, are hampered by the noise of the effects of the reputation layer, which is very varied in the field.</p>
<p>Reputation and validator admission are high hurdles in PBFT chains, which is very different from Nakamoto consensus (which assumes no trusted root). But given that many of the security guarantees are arguable coming from "walking the graph", it seems that there may be optimizations in reducing the overpayment.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>The validators must receive a payment for their services. The challenge for all token holders is determining what is the correct fee to pay operators given that a) validator opportunity cost is extrinsic to chain b) the validators preferences (utility) is private.</p>
<p>If blockchains underpay, trust from the users goes down as fewer nodes participate. As a result, the security guarantees for halts and writes go down, and the subjective political neutrality of the chain is lowered. While perhaps a reasonable but imperfect assumption, that more payment always increases security, the designers of blockchain economics usually err on the side of overpaying for consensus.</p>
<div class="codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-text codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar" style="color:#393A34;background-color:#f6f8fa"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">This is the end of Part 1. [In Part 2](http://openlibra.blog/2022/10/20/proof-of-fee-part-2-a-proposal/), we will explore the mechanics and implementations of an alternative approach, Proof of Fee.</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>PoF</category>
            <category>Proof of Fee</category>
            <category>canonical</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proposal 2210-2 - Proof of Fee]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Proposal Type: Signalling]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-type-signalling">Proposal Type: Signalling<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee#proposal-type-signalling" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling" title="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="champion-0o-de-lally">Champion: 0o-de-lally<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee#champion-0o-de-lally" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Champion: 0o-de-lally" title="Direct link to Champion: 0o-de-lally">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="date-13-october-2022">Date: 13 October 2022<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee#date-13-october-2022" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Date: 13 October 2022" title="Direct link to Date: 13 October 2022">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="state-draft--work-in-progress">State: Draft / Work in Progress<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee#state-draft--work-in-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to State: Draft / Work in Progress" title="Direct link to State: Draft / Work in Progress">​</a></h6>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="context"><strong>Context</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee#context" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to context" title="Direct link to context">​</a></h3>
<p>As an alternative to the (near-universally deployed) Delegated Proof of Stake we propose a sybil resistance technique designed natively for the benefits and tradeoffs of PBFT consensus, we call that system Proof-of-Fee (PoF). This proposal seeks to replace the Delay Towers mechanism currently in place with Proof-of-Fee.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Profits to blockchains are slim to non-existent. Low consensus costs are foundational for any chain that wishes to provide consumer surplus and profit to coin-holders; where excess winnings of the chain can be distributed to <em>all</em> account holders, that is, without preference to an investor class of "stakers". In PoF, the cost of consensus is lowered maximally to the <em>operator opportunity cost</em>, and such that the social cost (of dilution through issuance) is minimized.</p>
<p>Validator seats are auctioned at each epoch, such that the validators private valuation of rewards, MEV, breakage, and governance is revealed. PoF coins have superior ergonomics. Every actor has a very simple instruction; no staking, no yield games, no slashing. Holding the coin is the dominant strategy.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="synopsis"><strong>Synopsis</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee#synopsis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to synopsis" title="Direct link to synopsis">​</a></h3>
<p>Proof of Fee partially replaces the current security model of 0L, by introducing novel economic guarantees layered with the validator admission through Vouches and Jail reputation.</p>
<p>The proposal has two parts:</p>
<ol>
<li>Define a new validator incentives mechanism, and</li>
<li>Replace Delay Towers with Proof of Fee.</li>
</ol>
<p>Here’s how each part works:</p>
<p><strong>Part 1: Define a New Validator Incentives Structure (i.e., determining how much is paid)</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>0L will shift from the algorithmic calculation of validator incentives that we presently employ, to a fee that is a percentage of the total supply. The percentage is stable across epochs.</li>
<li>Each successful validator will receive an equal amount as other validators in incentives each epoch.</li>
<li>The amount of the fee is a parameter subject to governance action (and hence is adjustable on vote by the community).</li>
<li>The amount should be minimal (e.g., single digit percentages of the total supply per year) yet designed to provide adequate incentives for validators to secure and maintain a reliable network.</li>
<li>Incentives will be paid from the Infrastructure Escrow community wallet (see, Proposal 2210-1)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Part 2: Implement Proof of Fee&nbsp; (i.e., determining who gets to be paid)</strong></p>
<p>Proof of Fee creates a competitive auction mechanism to pick who gets to participate in the validator set each epoch. Here’s an overview of how it works, a thorough paper is forthcoming:</p>
<ul>
<li>At the beginning of each epoch, all validators who wish to participate in the epoch will place a bid (an Entry Fee).</li>
<li>There is a limit to the number of validators in an epoch, the ones with the highest bids will enter the epoch.</li>
<li>Validator consensus power is determined by the entry fee.</li>
<li>Each validator bids their highest entry fee, with the expectation of receiving a flat fee at the end of a successful epoch.</li>
<li>The initial proposed auction type is a Generalized Second Price Auction (a variation of the Nth Price Auction), which means the validator doesn't pay their maximum bid, but the bid of the next person immediately below them. (note: Future variations on this auction are possible and should be explored)</li>
<li>Bids in excess of the pre-defined validator incentive for that epoch (i.e., a negative bid) will be permitted, within limits (e.g. 110% of the reward). The limit is a parameter subject to governance action (and hence is adjustable on vote by the community)</li>
<li>At completion of the epoch, the pre-defined incentive amount will be paid to all validators that successfully completed the epoch. (The entry fee was already be paid thus, the net reward to a validator will be: Gross Incentive - Entry Fee = Net Amount Received by Each Validator)</li>
</ul>
<p>All actions will be included in the Version 6 upgrade to the Protocol.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting YES on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee#impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<p>A vote of YES on this proposal will signal to the Engineering Team and the Validator set the community’s desire to enact the following changes in the Version 6 Protocol Upgrade:</p>
<ol>
<li>Create new epoch reward amount, with parameter for governance,</li>
<li>If Final Supply proposal passes, then the validator reward will be extracted from the Infrastructure Escrow community wallet (no new coins will be minted).</li>
<li>Disable Delay Towers for Validator Sybil Resistance Purposes.</li>
<li>Implement Proof of Fee with all necessary dependencies</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting NO on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee#impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<p>A vote of NO on this proposal will reject all parts of this proposal and retain the Delay Towers mechanism that is currently in place.</p>
<ul>
<li>The author(s) believe that revision of our current approach to consensus is essential for the community, so in the event that you choose to vote against this proposal, we welcome you to engage with the community to collaborate on the creation of a policy that is acceptable to the community at large.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="special-notes"><strong>Special Notes:</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee#special-notes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to special-notes" title="Direct link to special-notes">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Note that this is a signalling proposal and therefore does not directly impact the chain; subsequent action is required to implement these changes.</li>
<li>The outcomes of this proposal can be modified by the community via a subsequent proposal and vote</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reference-materials"><strong>Reference Materials:</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee#reference-materials" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to reference-materials" title="Direct link to reference-materials">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>See also, Proposal 2210-1, Final Supply, for an explanation of the Infrastructure Escrow Community Wallet</li>
</ul>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="notes-on-process"><strong>Notes on Process</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-2-proof-of-fee#notes-on-process" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to notes-on-process" title="Direct link to notes-on-process">​</a></h4>
<ul>
<li>This document is a Draft / Work in Progress. It will change until marked as FINAL. <strong>The closing date for revisions is 15 October.</strong></li>
<li>Publication here is an invitation for community collaboration and co-creation.</li>
<li>To engage on this content, visit the <strong>#governance-proposals</strong> channel on the 0L Discord (link at bottom right)</li>
<li>Once this Proposal is finalized, it will be the subject of Voting on the Radical X Change platform. If you do not yet have credentials, visit the <strong>#rxc-voice-discussion</strong> channel on the 0L Discord and make a request to join.</li>
<li><strong>Voting opens 17 Oct and closes 22 Oct</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>governance</category>
            <category>proposal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proposal 2210-7 - Donor Directed Community Wallets]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-7-donor-directed-community-wallets</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-7-donor-directed-community-wallets</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Proposal Type: Signalling]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-type-signalling">Proposal Type: Signalling<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-7-donor-directed-community-wallets#proposal-type-signalling" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling" title="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="champion-tbd">Champion: TBD<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-7-donor-directed-community-wallets#champion-tbd" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Champion: TBD" title="Direct link to Champion: TBD">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="date-12-october-2022">Date: 12 October 2022<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-7-donor-directed-community-wallets#date-12-october-2022" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Date: 12 October 2022" title="Direct link to Date: 12 October 2022">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="state-draft--work-in-progress">State: Draft / Work in Progress<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-7-donor-directed-community-wallets#state-draft--work-in-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to State: Draft / Work in Progress" title="Direct link to State: Draft / Work in Progress">​</a></h6>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="context"><strong>Context</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-7-donor-directed-community-wallets#context" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to context" title="Direct link to context">​</a></h3>
<p>This proposal is focused on improving alignment of community wallets through governance levers.</p>
<p>As a reminder, all community wallets are owned by a real world entity, not by the chain. As such those real world entities have real world liabilities if they misuse the funds donated to them. This off chain governance layer is expensive and slow to catch problems. Smart contract capabilities can help create proper governance.</p>
<p>Current Challenges:</p>
<ul>
<li>Community wallets hold a great amount of coins, but most are inactive.</li>
<li>There is a perception that community wallets are for enrichment of participants (not donor directed funds for growth).</li>
<li>Stopping Community wallets from misbehaving is hard.</li>
</ul>
<p>There's nothing the protocol can do to take money away from community wallets, or to censure certain wallets. Forking and removing certain coins can be done by the validator set, though this is politically impossible. What can be done is to correct some of the governance issues in the wallets; this proposal seeks to do that.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="synopsis"><strong>Synopsis</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-7-donor-directed-community-wallets#synopsis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to synopsis" title="Direct link to synopsis">​</a></h3>
<p>There are five parts to this proposal to enhance Community Wallets.&nbsp;</p>
<p>**1.**<strong>Implement Donor Direction</strong></p>
<p>Typically within our community, the Community Wallets have been idealized and spoken about as being "donor directed". However we had no proper tracking on-chain of the donations to actually realize this vision. As an intermediary step, we said the validators would be the authorities over veto and freezing of these wallets. This was fine when there was a large overlap of donors and active validators, but today this has already diverged significantly.</p>
<p>We already have the donation tracking (the Receipts module) and with the v6 fork we can do two things to improve Community Wallet governance.</p>
<ul>
<li>Confirm that the values are correct per donor account (and sum to the value of donations), and</li>
<li>Update the voting mechanism to use the Receipts module, thereby enabling the donors to have oversight over the expenditures rather than depending on action by the validator set.</li>
</ul>
<p>**2.**<strong>Inclusion in the Burn Index</strong></p>
<p>Additionally, with the v6 fork we can also add Community Wallets to the Burn Index, which will give every account in 0L the option to have their costs (burns) be recycled to an index of community wallets.&nbsp;</p>
<p>**3.**<strong>Optimization of Voting Thresholds</strong></p>
<p>Since participation is low in community wallets and the monitoring tools are lacking, the voting thresholds for rejecting and ultimately freezing wallets should be lowered.</p>
<ul>
<li>A community wallet transaction should be rejected if 1/6th of the donors disapprove with a veto. Three consecutive Vetos would mean freezing of the account, no changes there.</li>
<li>There was no way to directly freeze a wallet. A wallet can also be frozen if 1/6th of the donors choose to do so. And can be unfrozen if 2/6th of the donors choose to do so.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>4.</strong> <strong>Define A Community Wallet as a Donor Directed Wallet with a Multisig</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The new Policy would be: For a community wallet to be included in the Burn Index, and for unrestricted transactions from Transfer and Autopay functionality, the wallet will have to have a minimum of 3 of 4 multisig. The multisig will be implemented in the Donor Directed contract (as opposed to by off-chain signing wallets).</li>
<li>Multisig signers for Community Wallets must have a threshold number of addresses that are unrelated (from different Ancestry in the permission trees).</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>5</strong>. <strong>Create tools for monitoring and reacting to community wallets</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Build monitoring and reporting into 0LExplorer.io</li>
<li>Create interactive reports on Carpe</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting YES on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-7-donor-directed-community-wallets#impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>Community Wallet policies will be changed to correct their behavior such that they are actually donor directed, and that they use multisigs for transaction approval.</li>
<li>Developers would be funded to create the code in line with the 5 changes outlined, above.</li>
<li>Carpe and 0L Explorer developers should be funded to create monitoring tools.</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting NO on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-7-donor-directed-community-wallets#impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>Community Wallets will continue to have low oversight by the people and entities that funded them.</li>
<li>It will be difficult to catch one bad actor who abuses the Burn Match Index mechanism, since it doesn't require a diverse multisig, and there are no monitoring tools.</li>
</ol>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reference-materials"><strong>Reference Materials:</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-7-donor-directed-community-wallets#reference-materials" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to reference-materials" title="Direct link to reference-materials">​</a></h4>
<ul>
<li>n/a</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Notes on Process</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>This document is a Draft / Work in Progress. It will change until marked as FINAL. <strong>The closing date for revisions is 15 October.</strong></li>
<li>Publication here is an invitation for community collaboration and co-creation.</li>
<li>To engage on this content, visit the <strong>#governance-proposals</strong> channel on the 0L Discord (link at bottom right)</li>
<li>Once this Proposal is finalized, it will be the subject of Voting on the Radical X Change platform. If you do not yet have credentials, visit the <strong>#rxc-voice-discussion</strong> channel on the 0L Discord and make a request to join.</li>
<li><strong>Voting opens 17 Oct and closes 22 Oct</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>governance</category>
            <category>proposal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proposal 2210-8 - Infrastructure Escrow Funding]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-8-infrastructure-escrow-funding</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-8-infrastructure-escrow-funding</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Proposal Type: Signalling]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-type-signalling">Proposal Type: Signalling<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-8-infrastructure-escrow-funding#proposal-type-signalling" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling" title="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="champion-0o-de-lally">Champion: 0o-de-lally<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-8-infrastructure-escrow-funding#champion-0o-de-lally" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Champion: 0o-de-lally" title="Direct link to Champion: 0o-de-lally">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="date-12-october-2022">Date: 12 October 2022<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-8-infrastructure-escrow-funding#date-12-october-2022" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Date: 12 October 2022" title="Direct link to Date: 12 October 2022">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="state-draft--work-in-progress">State: Draft / Work in Progress<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-8-infrastructure-escrow-funding#state-draft--work-in-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to State: Draft / Work in Progress" title="Direct link to State: Draft / Work in Progress">​</a></h6>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="context"><strong>Context</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-8-infrastructure-escrow-funding#context" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to context" title="Direct link to context">​</a></h3>
<p>If the Final Supply proposal (2210-1) passes, an Infrastructure Escrow Community Wallet will be created to provide future validator rewards; this is a replacement for the daily minting of coins. The need for validator incentives will remain after minting of new coins stops, and this fund is designed to fill that gap into the medium term future (5-10 years).&nbsp;</p>
<p>Note that the re-basing contemplated by the Final Supply proposal means that the total supply will increase by a multiple. That multiple can be applied equally to all wallet types or distributed among the wallet holders in a variety of unequal fashions. The funds for the Infrastructure Escrow Community Wallet have to come from somewhere. So, as the supply is increased by the re-basing, a portion of tokens need to be carved off and put into a Community Wallet to pay for future incentives. It is inevitable that someone has to be diluted. This proposal asks voters to signal how they want that burden to be distributed.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="synopsis"><strong>Synopsis</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-8-infrastructure-escrow-funding#synopsis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to synopsis" title="Direct link to synopsis">​</a></h3>
<p>The escrow fund should cover between 5 and 10 years of network infrastructure subsidies. To achieve that, wallets will have to be diluted. This proposal asks you how you prefer that dilution to occur; it asks you who do you want to see diluted. The options are:\</p>
<ol>
<li>Carpe Miners</li>
<li>Workers</li>
<li>Validators</li>
<li>Community Wallets</li>
</ol>
<p>Based on the expression of preference by the voters, a formula will be created.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Remember, this is a quadratic voting process so you can express strong preferences here if you so desire. Quadratic Voting shows conviction voting on each of these variants, and based on that we can estimate how much each party should pay and put that forward in a subsequent governance action.&nbsp;</p>
<p>(By way of example: If the community votes equally strongly to dilute all, then all accounts should be diluted. In contrast, if two of the categories of wallets stand out equally then those wallets would have the same dilution (while the other two none). And variations on this.)</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting YES on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-8-infrastructure-escrow-funding#impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>Voting Yes on any of the variants increases the share that the group in question will contribute to the infrastructure escrow. Voting with greater conviction will increase the share.</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting NO on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-8-infrastructure-escrow-funding#impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<p>Voting No on any variant, reduces the proportion that the group will contribute to the escrow fund. Voting NO with greater conviction reduces the share.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-abstaining-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Abstaining on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-8-infrastructure-escrow-funding#impact-of-abstaining-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-abstaining-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-abstaining-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>If you do not have conviction on these items, (you use your Quadratic Voting credits elsewhere) the proportions will be set by other voters.</li>
</ul>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reference-materials"><strong>Reference Materials</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-8-infrastructure-escrow-funding#reference-materials" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to reference-materials" title="Direct link to reference-materials">​</a></h4>
<ul>
<li>See also, <a href="http://openlibra.blog/2022/10/11/proposal-2210-1-final-supply/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Proposal 2210-1, Final Supply</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Notes on Process</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>This document is a Draft / Work in Progress. It will change until marked as FINAL. <strong>The closing date for revisions is 15 October.</strong></li>
<li>Publication here is an invitation for community collaboration and co-creation.</li>
<li>To engage on this content, visit the <strong>#governance-proposals</strong> channel on the 0L Discord (link at bottom right)</li>
<li>Once this Proposal is finalized, it will be the subject of Voting on the Radical X Change platform. If you do not yet have credentials, visit the <strong>#rxc-voice-discussion</strong> channel on the 0L Discord and make a request to join.</li>
<li><strong>Voting opens 17 Oct and closes 22 Oct</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>governance</category>
            <category>proposal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proposal 2210-1 - Final Supply]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-1-final-supply</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-1-final-supply</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Proposal Type: Signalling]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-type-signalling">Proposal Type: <strong>Signalling</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-1-final-supply#proposal-type-signalling" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to proposal-type-signalling" title="Direct link to proposal-type-signalling">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="champion-ricoflan">Champion: <strong>ricoflan</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-1-final-supply#champion-ricoflan" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to champion-ricoflan" title="Direct link to champion-ricoflan">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="date-11-october-2022">Date: <strong>11 October 2022</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-1-final-supply#date-11-october-2022" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to date-11-october-2022" title="Direct link to date-11-october-2022">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="state-draft--work-in-progress">State: <strong>Draft / Work In Progress</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-1-final-supply#state-draft--work-in-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to state-draft--work-in-progress" title="Direct link to state-draft--work-in-progress">​</a></h6>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="context"><strong>Context</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-1-final-supply#context" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to context" title="Direct link to context">​</a></h3>
<p>This proposal relates to the biggest opportunity 0L has. With this proposal, the community is in a unique position to create a balanced, equitable approach to sustainability in which all participants are of a single class: All participants are workers.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The current 0L token issuance schema is dramatically diluting workers while enriching the validators via issuance of new tokens each epoch (i.e., inflation). Anyone who has earned bounties, or engineering funds, have had their value reduced significantly by inflation across the last 6 months. This needs to change.</p>
<p>The challenge to stopping inflation is how to preserve incentives for validators without ongoing issuance. This proposal seeks to stop inflation by ending issuance while providing a means to fund validator incentives for the medium to long term.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="synopsis"><strong>Synopsis</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-1-final-supply#synopsis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to synopsis" title="Direct link to synopsis">​</a></h3>
<p>This proposal seeks to scaffold a permanently deflationary coin. There are three parts to the proposal: (1) stop issuance; (2) rebase the token; (3) create and fund an Infrastructure Escrow community wallet to provide validator rewards. The proposal asks for a single vote on all three parts; the three parts are interconnected and dependent.</p>
<ol>
<li>Stop Issuance: The first part of this proposal is the simplest: Stop issuance of new tokens.</li>
<li>Rebase the Token: In order to fund the Infrastructure Escrow wallet (see, #3 below), there must be some form of dilution. The simplest, and most regulatory compliant way is to rebase the existing token by splitting each coin by approximately 5 (final calculations TBD) such that the total final supply is 10B coins. This in effect expands significantly the supply in a one time action; all account holders will have a higher account balance after the rebasing. (Note that this proposal only establishes a mandate to rebase; the exact methodology will be the subject of a separate, subsequent governance action if this passes.)</li>
<li>Create and Fund the Infrastructure Escrow community wallet: A new community wallet will be created to serve as an escrow for future validator rewards. This wallet will be funded from the tokens created by the rebasing of the token (see #2, above).&nbsp; (Note that this proposal only establishes a mandate to create and fund; the exact methodology will be the subject of a separate, subsequent governance action if this passes.)</li>
</ol>
<p>All three actions will be included in the Version 6 upgrade to the Protocol.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting YES on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-1-final-supply#impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<p>A vote of YES on this proposal will signal to the Engineering Team and the Validator set the community’s desire to enact the following changes in the Version 6 Protocol Upgrade:</p>
<ol>
<li>Stop issuance of tokens</li>
<li>Rebase the token using a formula to be determined in subsequent governance action</li>
<li>Create a new community wallet named Infrastructure Escrow</li>
<li>Transfer into that wallet a number of tokens to be determined by subsequent governance action</li>
<li>Note the impact of the passage of this proposal on token holders in multi-fold:<!-- -->
<ol>
<li>There will be more tokens in the system.</li>
<li>All wallets will show higher balances.</li>
<li>A formula will be devised to allocate a portion of those tokens from all wallets to the new Infrastructure Escrow. That formula will need to be determined in subsequent governance actions.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting NO on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-1-final-supply#impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<p>A vote of NO on this proposal will reject all parts of this proposal and issuance-driven inflation will remain in effect as it is currently.</p>
<ul>
<li>The author(s) believe that a clear path to a mission-aligned revision of our tokenomics is essential for the community, so in the event that you choose to vote against this proposal, we welcome you to engage with the community to collaborate on the creation of a policy that is acceptable to the community at large.</li>
</ul>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="special-notes"><strong>Special Notes:</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-1-final-supply#special-notes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to special-notes" title="Direct link to special-notes">​</a></h4>
<ul>
<li>Note that this is a signalling proposal and therefore does not directly impact the chain; subsequent action is required to implement these changes.</li>
<li>The outcomes of this proposal can be modified by the community via a subsequent proposal and vote</li>
</ul>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reference-materials"><strong>Reference Materials:</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-1-final-supply#reference-materials" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to reference-materials" title="Direct link to reference-materials">​</a></h4>
<ul>
<li>See also, Proposal 2210-8, Infrastructure Escrow Funding</li>
</ul>
<p>Notes on Process</p>
<ul>
<li>This document is a Draft / Work in Progress. It will change until marked as FINAL. <strong>The closing date for revisions is 15 October</strong>.</li>
<li>Publication here is an invitation for community collaboration and co-creation.</li>
<li>To engage on this content, visit the <strong>#governance-proposals</strong> channel on the 0L Discord (link at bottom right)</li>
<li>Once this Proposal is finalized, it will be the subject of Voting on the Radical X Change platform. If you do not yet have credentials, visit the <strong>#rxc-voice-discussion</strong> channel on the 0L Discord and make a request to join.</li>
<li><strong>Voting opens 17 Oct and closes 22 Oct</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>governance</category>
            <category>proposal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proposal 2210-4 - Repurpose Carpe]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-4-repurpose-carpe</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-4-repurpose-carpe</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Proposal Type: Signalling]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-type-signalling">Proposal Type: Signalling<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-4-repurpose-carpe#proposal-type-signalling" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling" title="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="champion-tbd">Champion: TBD<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-4-repurpose-carpe#champion-tbd" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Champion: TBD" title="Direct link to Champion: TBD">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="date-11-october-2022">Date: 11 October 2022<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-4-repurpose-carpe#date-11-october-2022" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Date: 11 October 2022" title="Direct link to Date: 11 October 2022">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="state-draft--work-in-progress">State: Draft / Work in Progress<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-4-repurpose-carpe#state-draft--work-in-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to State: Draft / Work in Progress" title="Direct link to State: Draft / Work in Progress">​</a></h6>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="context"><strong>Context</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-4-repurpose-carpe#context" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to context" title="Direct link to context">​</a></h3>
<p>If Proposal 2210-2 Proof of Fee passes, the need for Towers will be eliminated and Carpe users will have nothing to do. This proposal advocates for one approach (an oracle service) to creating utility for Carpe. Additionally, 0L is seeking to have more revenue opportunities for the chain and expanded functionality. Oracles are ways of getting off-chain data onto the chain, e.g. getting the price of a coin from a website. The design does not foreclose other future uses for Carpe.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="synopsis"><strong>Synopsis</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-4-repurpose-carpe#synopsis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to synopsis" title="Direct link to synopsis">​</a></h3>
<p>This proposal advocates that we take advantage of the Carpe installed base and repurpose Carpe into an Oracle Protocol, which in the future would be another source of revenue. Common oracle use cases are for the scraping of pricing data and exposing it on chain for apps to consume the data. Other similar uses are also possible. As such, oracles are a foundational piece of blockchain architecture that enables other services to function onchain in 0L.</p>
<ul>
<li>While the nature and pricing of the service will require subsequent governance action, a simple revenue model could work like this: The Oracle service will charge fee for its data stream that revenue should be designed to cover the Carpe costs.</li>
<li>When revenue surpasses Carpe costs, then the remainder should be burned (i.e. redistributed to all accounts).</li>
<li>Initially, as revenues ramp up, a subsidy will be needed to keep Carpe users mining until the Oracle product is complete.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting YES on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-4-repurpose-carpe#impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>Tower mining, and the Identity Subsidy, by Carpe will NOT stop when towers are discontinued with Proof of Fee. It will continue until an Oracle subsidy or Oracle product can be introduced.</li>
<li>The Engineering team will design and build an oracle function for Carpe Miners</li>
<li>The oracle upgrade will be distributed for on-chain policy upgrades (AKA Stdlib), and upgrades to Carpe.</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting NO on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-4-repurpose-carpe#impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<p>&nbsp;If this proposal is defeated, Carpe mining will have no reward, and Carpe will continue only as a wallet.</p>
<ul>
<li>If Delay Towers are abandoned (as per Proposal 2210-2 Proof of Fee, or other governance action), then Carpe will cease to function.</li>
<li>Note that if this proposal is defeated, there will remain a need to explore future expansion of Carpe functionality, or the sunsetting of the Carpe app. The author encourages those who vote No on this proposal to work with the community to find a means to address these challenges.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reference-materials"><strong>Reference Materials</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-4-repurpose-carpe#reference-materials" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to reference-materials" title="Direct link to reference-materials">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>See Proposal 2210-2, Proof of Fee, for an explanation of Proof of Fee and how that would replace Delay Towers.</li>
</ul>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="notes-on-process"><strong>Notes on Process</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-4-repurpose-carpe#notes-on-process" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to notes-on-process" title="Direct link to notes-on-process">​</a></h4>
<ul>
<li>This document is a Draft / Work in Progress. It will change until marked as FINAL. The closing date for revisions is 15 October.</li>
<li>Publication here is an invitation for community collaboration and co-creation.</li>
<li>To engage on this content, visit the <strong>#governance-proposals</strong> channel on the 0L Discord (link at bottom right)</li>
<li>Once this Proposal is finalized, it will be the subject of Voting on the Radical X Change platform. If you do not yet have credentials, visit the <strong>#rxc-voice-discussion</strong> channel on the 0L Discord and make a request to join.</li>
<li><strong>Voting opens 17 Oct and closes 22 Oct</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>governance</category>
            <category>proposal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proposal 2210-5 - Revenue Binding Primitives]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-5-revenue-binding-primitives</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-5-revenue-binding-primitives</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Proposal Type: Signalling]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-type-signalling">Proposal Type: Signalling<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-5-revenue-binding-primitives#proposal-type-signalling" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling" title="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="champion-tbd">Champion: TBD<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-5-revenue-binding-primitives#champion-tbd" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Champion: TBD" title="Direct link to Champion: TBD">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="date-11-october-2022">Date: 11 October 2022<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-5-revenue-binding-primitives#date-11-october-2022" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Date: 11 October 2022" title="Direct link to Date: 11 October 2022">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="state-draftwork-in-progress">State: Draft/Work in Progress<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-5-revenue-binding-primitives#state-draftwork-in-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to State: Draft/Work in Progress" title="Direct link to State: Draft/Work in Progress">​</a></h6>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="context"><strong>Context</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-5-revenue-binding-primitives#context" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to context" title="Direct link to context">​</a></h3>
<p>The community has signaled the importance of profitable unit economics. Experimentation is needed in order to create revenue streams from a) new protocol products, b) third party applications and c) off-chain businesses. Currently in the 0L tech stack, there are few functions, or bindings for that experimentation take place. This proposal advocates for the network to create this foundational tooling.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="synopsis"><strong>Synopsis</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-5-revenue-binding-primitives#synopsis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to synopsis" title="Direct link to synopsis">​</a></h3>
<p>Develop new protocol services. Third party apps, and offline protocols need an easy way to charge fees in 0L coins. Priorities:</p>
<ul>
<li>Helpers in DiemAccount.move to facilitate future products<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>Bridge</li>
<li>Name service</li>
<li>Indexing Service</li>
<li>Exchange</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Applications and Off-chain Scaffolds for Revenue<!-- -->
<ul>
<li>Create App revenue bindings</li>
<li>Simple transaction capabilities, tracking, and bindings should be provided.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting YES on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-5-revenue-binding-primitives#impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>The 0L standard library will be extended so that developers can easily charge fees in 0L coins, which will help generate revenue to the chain.</li>
<li>Engineers will be funded to work on developing a spec and delivering the code.</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting NO on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-5-revenue-binding-primitives#impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>This will not be worked on at the moment, and third party developers need to issue their own coins for apps.</li>
</ol>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reference-materials"><strong>Reference Materials</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-5-revenue-binding-primitives#reference-materials" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to reference-materials" title="Direct link to reference-materials">​</a></h4>
<ul>
<li>n/a</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Notes on Process</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>This document is a Draft / Work in Progress. It will change until marked as FINAL. The closing date for revisions is 15 October.</li>
<li>Publication here is an invitation for community collaboration and co-creation.</li>
<li>To engage on this content, visit the <strong>#governance-proposals</strong> channel on the 0L Discord (link at bottom right)</li>
<li>Once this Proposal is finalized, it will be the subject of Voting on the Radical X Change platform. If you do not yet have credentials, visit the <strong>#rxc-voice-discussion</strong> channel on the 0L Discord and make a request to join.</li>
<li><strong>Voting opens 17 Oct and closes 22 Oct</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>governance</category>
            <category>proposal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proposal 2210-6 - Faucets for Workers]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-6-faucets-for-workers</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-6-faucets-for-workers</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Proposal Type: Signalling]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-type-signalling">Proposal Type: Signalling<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-6-faucets-for-workers#proposal-type-signalling" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling" title="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="champion-tbd">Champion: TBD<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-6-faucets-for-workers#champion-tbd" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Champion: TBD" title="Direct link to Champion: TBD">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="date-11-october-2022">Date: 11 October 2022<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-6-faucets-for-workers#date-11-october-2022" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Date: 11 October 2022" title="Direct link to Date: 11 October 2022">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="state-draftwork-in-progress">State: Draft/Work in Progress<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-6-faucets-for-workers#state-draftwork-in-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to State: Draft/Work in Progress" title="Direct link to State: Draft/Work in Progress">​</a></h6>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="context"><strong>Context</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-6-faucets-for-workers#context" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to context" title="Direct link to context">​</a></h3>
<p>The proposals Proof of Fee (2210-2) and Final Supply (2210-1) are targeted at adjusting rewards from validators, with the goal of incentivizing the best performing validators. In line with the vision of creating an entrepreneurial cooperative, the 0L Network should also have a low-friction way for workers to organize themselves and receive streams of payments, in the absence of algorithmic rewards. This proposal takes a first step in that direction.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="synopsis"><strong>Synopsis</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-6-faucets-for-workers#synopsis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to synopsis" title="Direct link to synopsis">​</a></h3>
<p>This proposal advocates for the Engineering team to prioritize the development of functionality that will enable a simple mechanism for routing payments to working via the creation of a Move 0L framework (AKA stdlib) tools for entities to create and fund faucets. Features would include:</p>
<ol>
<li>Anyone can start a Faucet</li>
<li>Faucets can have one or more administrators</li>
<li>The faucet can receive donations (from Community Wallets or users).</li>
<li>A user can claim a self-service payment from a faucet</li>
</ol>
<p>The self-service aspects of the faucets will be gated, as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>The more users claiming the longer it takes for payment to process.</li>
<li>The payment happens automatically unless an administrator intervenes.</li>
<li>Certain faucets may require credentials (an NFT) before one can join.</li>
</ul>
<p>A leading use case for this would be the Hustle Karma DAO, which can reduce overhead and speed payments by allowing users to self-paying for their work.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting YES on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-6-faucets-for-workers#impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>Faucets would become an 0L stdlib feature which Community Wallets and others could use.</li>
<li>An engineering group would be funded to develop the Faucets tooling. The code would be merged to Move Stdlib on completion.</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting NO on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-6-faucets-for-workers#impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>No Engineering effort in this area would be undertaken absent additional governance action.</li>
</ul>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reference-materials"><strong>Reference Materials</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-6-faucets-for-workers#reference-materials" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to reference-materials" title="Direct link to reference-materials">​</a></h4>
<ul>
<li>n/a</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Notes on Process</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>This document is a Draft / Work in Progress. It will change until marked as FINAL. The closing date for revisions is 15 October.</li>
<li>Publication here is an invitation for community collaboration and co-creation.</li>
<li>To engage on this content, visit the <strong>#governance-proposals</strong> channel on the 0L Discord (link at bottom right)</li>
<li>Once this Proposal is finalized, it will be the subject of Voting on the Radical X Change platform. If you do not yet have credentials, visit the <strong>#rxc-voice-discussion</strong> channel on the 0L Discord and make a request to join.</li>
<li><strong>Voting opens 17 Oct and closes 22 Oct</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>governance</category>
            <category>proposal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proposal 2210-3 - Musical Chairs]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Proposal Type: Signalling]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proposal-type-signalling">Proposal Type: Signalling<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs#proposal-type-signalling" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling" title="Direct link to Proposal Type: Signalling">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="champion-tbd">Champion: TBD<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs#champion-tbd" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Champion: TBD" title="Direct link to Champion: TBD">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="date-10-october-2022">Date: 10 October 2022<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs#date-10-october-2022" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Date: 10 October 2022" title="Direct link to Date: 10 October 2022">​</a></h6>
<h6 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="status-draft--work-in-progress">Status: Draft / Work in Progress<a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs#status-draft--work-in-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Status: Draft / Work in Progress" title="Direct link to Status: Draft / Work in Progress">​</a></h6>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="context"><strong>Context</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs#context" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to context" title="Direct link to context">​</a></h3>
<p>0L hasn't attempted to use Proof of Stake to filter malicious actors. Historically, we have had multiple layers of sybil resistance to prevent a malicious actor from amplifying attacks by multiplying the nodes they have access to. Vouches, social dynamics, and Delay Towers all work collectively to provide some resistance to bad actors. The mechanisms implemented to date have been sufficient for bootstrapping but are likely to prove inadequate at steady state.</p>
<p>The current design of 0L makes it such that validators compete less among themselves as the count of nodes expands. For example, at 60 seats, the next epoch will have 10 slots open (the network always makes ⅙ the number of seats available). This means the competition is lower as the network progressively increases, which may be counter to the needs of the network. Meaning: when the validator set is large, the performance in TPS goes down, and better higher-quality validators are needed (not more seats with validators of unknown quality). Also when the set is large, it may also intersect with be that demand for the network services being are high. In those cases we want more, or at least the same, amount of competition.</p>
<p>The validator set needs to be optimized for both performance and reliablility. The current selection process utilized by 0L optimizes for neither of those attributes, being based instead, on purely numerical conditions. A revised approach could advance both performance and reliability.</p>
<p>It is expected that implementing the process described in this proposal will result in:</p>
<ol>
<li>Greater competition</li>
<li>Higher performance in vulnerable conditions</li>
<li>Lower costs to the network</li>
<li>Competition at any size</li>
</ol>
<p>We expect validator selection to be more competitive than the current design. By reducing the ⅙ expansion criteria to a fixed 1 seat, only when perfect performance is achieved by the collective, then we expect that there will be greater competition for the validator set.</p>
<p>Performant validators are not guaranteed a position, except when the network is vulnerable. In the case of subsequent reductions in the validator set because of extrinsic factors, the validator set progressively reduces to the most performant nodes, before becoming competitive again.</p>
<p>What Musical Chairs modifies, is that in a shrinking event, the validators which performed are guaranteed a seat. But as soon as a new seat opens up, then all validators must again compete on price (Delay Towers or Proof of Fee proposal)</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="synopsis"><strong>Synopsis</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs#synopsis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to synopsis" title="Direct link to synopsis">​</a></h3>
<p>With musical chairs, the validator set has no maximum limit. Whatever it's size (M) it is currently at its limit. Validators compete for seats through normal mechanism (Tower height) or a different cost (Proof of Fee), when the validator set is performant.</p>
<p>Whenever the validator set has perfect performance by all nodes, the set can increase by 1 seat (M + 1). No validators are guaranteed a seat when the seat count is stable or growing. They compete on the lowest cost of service provided (cost of consensus). In the event of a validator set where one node did not perform (M - 1), then the next epoch will include all the performant validators LESS the one non-performing (the new size is M - 1).</p>
<p>There key attributes of Musical Chairs are:</p>
<ol>
<li>The validator set has no fixed upper bound of validator seats (i.e., no longer fixed at 100).</li>
<li>The validator set only expands if every member of the validator set performed above threshold - and then it only increases by 1 seat.</li>
<li>If any validator(s) did not perform, the validator set is reduced by the size of the non-performing validator(s) - and the expansion begins again.</li>
<li>In a shrunk validator set, all of the performant validators are allowed to remain, though if the validator set resumes increasing, they must compete on cost.</li>
</ol>
<p>All actions will be included in the Version 6 upgrade to the Protocol.</p>
<p>A vote of YES on this proposal will signal to the Engineering Team and the Validator set the community’s desire to enact the following changes in the Version 6 Protocol Upgrade:</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting YES on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs#impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-yes-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>Create the Musical Chairs functionality and all necessary dependencies</li>
<li>Disable the present validator selection set methodology</li>
<li>Implement Musical Chairs</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal"><strong>Impact of Voting NO on this Proposal</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs#impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal" title="Direct link to impact-of-voting-no-on-this-proposal">​</a></h3>
<p>A vote of NO on this proposal will reject all parts of this proposal and retain the validator set sizing mechanism that is currently in place.</p>
<ul>
<li>The author(s) believe that revision of our current approach to validator set sizing is essential for the community, so in the event that you choose to vote against this proposal, we welcome you to engage with the community to collaborate on the creation of a policy that is acceptable to the community at large.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="special-notes"><strong>Special Notes:</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs#special-notes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to special-notes" title="Direct link to special-notes">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Note that this is a signalling proposal and therefore does not directly impact the chain; subsequent action is required to implement these changes.</li>
<li>The outcomes of this proposal can be modified by the community via a subsequent proposal and vote</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reference-materials"><strong>Reference Materials:</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs#reference-materials" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to reference-materials" title="Direct link to reference-materials">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>See also, Proposal 2210-2, Final Supply, for an explanation of Proof of Fee, which is closely related to this proposal</li>
</ul>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="notes-on-process"><strong>Notes on Process</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/proposal-2210-3-musical-chairs#notes-on-process" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to notes-on-process" title="Direct link to notes-on-process">​</a></h4>
<ul>
<li>This document is a Draft / Work in Progress. It will change until marked as FINAL. The closing date for revisions is 15 October.</li>
<li>Publication here is an invitation for community collaboration and co-creation.</li>
<li>To engage on this content, visit the <strong>#governance-proposals</strong> channel on the 0L Discord (link at bottom right)</li>
<li>Once this Proposal is finalized, it will be the subject of Voting on the Radical X Change platform. If you do not yet have credentials, visit the <strong>#rxc-voice-discussion</strong> channel on the 0L Discord and make a request to join.</li>
<li><strong>Voting opens 17 Oct and closes 22 Oct</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>governance</category>
            <category>proposal</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Milestones for Carpe]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/new-milestones-for-carpe</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/new-milestones-for-carpe</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The 0L Network today reached a new record in terms of activity on the network: The daily number of active Carpe miners topped 2,000 for the first time today, with 2,080 installations running and earning tokens today. The number of active Carpe miners has been increasing steadily across the last 30 days, as new users have joined the community and discovered how easy it is to run Carpe and earn rewards.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 0L Network today reached a new record in terms of activity on the network: The daily number of active Carpe miners topped 2,000 for the first time today, with 2,080 installations running and earning tokens today. The number of active Carpe miners has been increasing steadily across the last 30 days, as new users have joined the community and discovered how easy it is to run Carpe and earn rewards.</p>
<p>Also on this date we have released a newly updated version of Carpe - version 0.5.0. Here's what's new:</p>
<ul>
<li>Wallet-to-wallet coin transfers</li>
<li>Better reliability connecting to the chain</li>
<li>Dynamic VDF proofs (improving network and miner performance!)</li>
<li>Over-the-air upgrades</li>
<li>Support for localization in multiple new languages</li>
</ul>
<p>For the next few days, you will need to manually download and install Carpe. The automatic updater will be enabled after we’ve given our more experienced users a chance to install the new version manually and report back on their experience.</p>
<p>Here are the links for the packages you need for a manual update:</p>
<ul>
<li>Windows users: <a href="https://github.com/0LNetworkCommunity/carpe/releases/download/v0.5.0/carpe_0.5.0_x64.msi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/0LNetworkCommunity/carpe/releases/download/v0.5.0/carpe_0.5.0_x64.msi</a></li>
<li>MacOS users (11+ only): <a href="https://github.com/0LNetworkCommunity/carpe/releases/download/v0.5.0/carpe-macos-11.dmg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/0LNetworkCommunity/carpe/releases/download/v0.5.0/carpe-macos-11.dmg</a></li>
<li>Debian users: <a href="https://github.com/0LNetworkCommunity/carpe/releases/download/v0.5.0/carpe_0.5.0_amd64.deb" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/0LNetworkCommunity/carpe/releases/download/v0.5.0/carpe_0.5.0_amd64.deb</a></li>
</ul>
<p>For those of you unfamiliar with Carpe, it is a wallet and light miner application that can run on most consumer computers. The app only requires 1 thread of your CPU, meaning not only can most machines run it, but you can run it in the background while you do other things with your machine. Download Carpe, learn about 0L and start receiving rewards - it’s very easy to get started.</p>
<p>Kudos to all of the Carpe contributors and the top-tier 0L community for pressing on during this crypto winter. It’s time for builders to build! We welcome all builders into the community and encourage you to explore this site to learn more and <a href="https://discord.gg/Nw7MpczV4X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">drop by our Discord and say hi</a>.</p>
<p>Carpe diem!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>carpe</category>
            <category>wallet</category>
            <category>software</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[0L Network Constitution]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/the-0l-network-constitution</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/the-0l-network-constitution</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Adopted by Community Polling on 3 May 2022]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Adopted by Community Polling on 3 May 2022</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="purpose-of-this-document"><strong>Purpose of this Document</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/the-0l-network-constitution#purpose-of-this-document" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to purpose-of-this-document" title="Direct link to purpose-of-this-document">​</a></h2>
<p>This document is intended as an exposition of shared values at the heart of the 0L Network Community. The principles espoused herein are provided as a framework for decisions at a macro level and have been drafted to inform the decision process and provide a foundation to facilitate consistent and rational decision-making. This Constitution should be treated as a living document that is extensible – within the framework of our core values – as the community grows.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="our-core-values"><strong>Our Core Values</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/proposals/the-0l-network-constitution#our-core-values" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to our-core-values" title="Direct link to our-core-values">​</a></h2>
<p>From our genesis, we have avoided the creation of an insider class (like a foundation, a protocol team, or venture capital investors) that might lead us down the path toward plutocracy. By creating an egalitarian community we hope to give the power of this blockchain to those that might do good for both our community and the wider world. We, as a community, seek to empower visionary entrepreneurs who hope to harness our chain to address problems at the intersection of information, economics and social coordination. To that end, we have adopted the following core values, which will serve as the underpinnings for critical decisions and our long term roadmap:&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>1. Merit</strong>: We are a community of do-ers who believe that those who serve our community and its vision should be rewarded &amp; given a voice in shaping our community’s future.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>2. Equity:</strong> We are a democratic community that values fairness. We welcome all and actively seek to avoid descending into plutocracy.</p>
<p><strong>3. Diversity</strong>: We strive to build an inclusive and diverse set of stakeholders, as we recognize that a diverse community is a resilient community.</p>
<p><strong>4. Network Integrity</strong>: We take the state and security of the network seriously and will not lightly take actions that impair or threaten them.</p>
<p><strong>5. Decentralization</strong>: The project should always strive towards decentralization.</p>
<p><strong>6. Permissionless:</strong> We will strive to keep the network and the community open to all.</p>
<p><strong>7. Do Good</strong>: We believe that generating positive social impact is everyone’s responsibility and we pledge a portion of this community’s output to furthering social good and humanitarian relief.</p>
<p><strong>Related Documents</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://openlibra.blog/2021/11/15/libra-liberated/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Libra Liberated</a>, (15 Nov 2021)</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>governance</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spring Forward]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/spring-forward </link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/spring-forward </guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Growth requires challenge]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Growth requires challenge</p>
<p>There was plenty of such fuel over the last several weeks, challenging our community to run a functional and fair network that is more poised for growth. This announcement will detail what has happened, how we addressed it and how, along the way, we solved a number of different problems and improved prospects going forward.</p>
<p>On 9 April 2022, the 0L Network halted. Multiple factors combined to create the incident; factors that started small and cascaded until the entire network ceased to produce blocks. While the detailed causes and the technical forensics have been discussed at length in our community meetings, the important point to raise here is that the halt was avoidable – or rather would have been avoidable – had a sufficient number within our validator community been more attentive to their machines and taken steps in a timely fashion. Better coordination is a key learning derived from this event.</p>
<p>With the network stopped, the community decided to take the time to make some major changes and bring back a network that was better and stronger and more aligned to the broader community’s interests. <strong>As you read this, the network is back, with a new set of features and a richer set of options for developers, Carpe miners, and the community as a whole.</strong></p>
<p>Among the enhancements we’ve launched with this new version of the 0L Network:</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="carpe-enhancements"><strong>Carpe Enhancements</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/spring-forward%C2%A0#carpe-enhancements" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to carpe-enhancements" title="Direct link to carpe-enhancements">​</a></h3>
<p>Together with this network upgrade, we will shortly be releasing a new version of the Carpe wallet and desktop miner. With this release, Carpe will attain full wallet functionality, with the ability for users to send and receive coins using a standard wallet interface. The new release is in testing now and will be announced soon. The Internet of Value needs money in motion.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="make-whole"><strong>Make Whole</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/spring-forward%C2%A0#make-whole" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to make-whole" title="Direct link to make-whole">​</a></h3>
<p>With this upgrade, we have set up a methodology for Carpe miners to claim coins that were under-paid to them in several past epochs due to a network bug. The Make Whole proposal has already been approved by the community, and we have set up a process that can be executed easily from inside Carpe to do so (you can learn more about this, and the new version of Carpe, once the release date is formalized).</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="slow-wallets"><strong>Slow Wallets</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/spring-forward%C2%A0#slow-wallets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to slow-wallets" title="Direct link to slow-wallets">​</a></h3>
<p>Slow wallet holders, particularly the members of our Hustle Karma workforce, will be pleased to learn that we have also used this upgrade to ease limitations on slow wallets. As of today, you can use your Carpe slow wallets to move coins! Daily transaction limits remain in place for slow wallets, at the level of 1,000 Libra per day. (Note that the daily transaction limit parameter is subject to adjustment by the community at a future date.) The goal is to balance active labor participation and value accrual with fair vesting and spending.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="recovery-tools"><strong>Recovery Tools</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/spring-forward%C2%A0#recovery-tools" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to recovery-tools" title="Direct link to recovery-tools">​</a></h3>
<p>A new set of recovery tools and workflows to make the network better able to recover from shocks in the future. There were a number of refactors to the writeset-tool, which enables a halted network to apply transactions at rest to upgrade the state machine code, update validator set, trigger new epochs, and enter recovery mode. Future halts could have very minimal downtime if the root cause is found quickly.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="addressing-the-larger-problem"><strong>Addressing the Larger Problem</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/spring-forward%C2%A0#addressing-the-larger-problem" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to addressing-the-larger-problem" title="Direct link to addressing-the-larger-problem">​</a></h2>
<p>The tools and actions listed above are important and worth celebrating. However, we have a larger social issue that needs resolution – that is, the negative impact of passive validators.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The recent outage shows the need to take action to better align validator incentives with the best interests of the broader 0L Network community. There is a very good argument that the recent network stoppage was less a technical problem than a problem of misalignment of incentives and expectations. We need to take steps to assure an engaged, professional validator set and we also need to change the competitive dynamics for validators in order to disincentivize passive validators.&nbsp;</p>
<p>To tackle the first issue, we are implementing a new approach to validator set selection. At the launch of the network, validators were entitled to invite whomever they chose to join the validator set. The system had no checks in place, other than a rate limit on how frequently invitations could be issued. We initially counted on social pressure and common sense to guide our validators to select individuals or organizations who were able to manage their nodes to a professional level, and who would respect system requirements.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, we now have experience showing that a more rigorous approach is needed. Indeed, the initial failures that began the cascade that led to the most recent network halt occurred first with the nodes that were under-provisioned and not in line with our published system requirements. Those failures were then complicated by many of those validators failing to be responsive to their machines and take remedial steps to recover from the failure.</p>
<p>Going forward, we are layering in a “vouching” system for validator set selection. At every epoch the system will check that each validator entering the set has endorsement by at least 4 existing validators of different "ancestry" . We mitigate the sybil issues by checking that the vouches come from&nbsp; different “family trees” (i.e., who onboarded them). Every epoch, you can only join the validator set if you have at least 4 peers known to be good actors vouching for you. To facilitate this requirement, we have created an onchain permission tree that makes it easy to trace the lineage of individual validators.&nbsp;</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="funding-the-community-via-proof-of-burn"><strong>Funding the Community via Proof of Burn</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/spring-forward%C2%A0#funding-the-community-via-proof-of-burn" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to funding-the-community-via-proof-of-burn" title="Direct link to funding-the-community-via-proof-of-burn">​</a></h3>
<p>The second issue – the competitive dynamics of the validator class – is somewhat more complex. The goal is to make the cost to exist as a validator higher, and thereby disincentivize passive validators (free riders). To accomplish this aim, we are making two changes.</p>
<p>First, we are putting in place a more expensive Proof of Burn mechanism. At launch, Proof of Burn was a fixed and insubstantial amount: Each validator was charged 1 coin per epoch to join the validator set. We also implemented a voluntary autopay function that encouraged validators to redirect a portion of their rewards to community wallets. The mechanism was 0L’s answer to how to capitalize the system’s growth and expansion in the absence of outside capital.&nbsp;</p>
<p>By increasing the Proof of Burn we can also automate community wallet funding by making it simpler and more seamless for those who opt-in. We’re increasing the burn from 1 coin to 50% of validator rewards. Those funds will be distributed each epoch among the community wallets based on donations to those wallets. Validators also have the option to give more than 50% if they wish, and if they do not want to divert the funds to the community wallets, they can elect to have the coins burned. Note that this change simply streamlines the autopay functionality that has been tested since the Genesis of the network.</p>
<p>Second, we are closing a loophole in the system’s capitalization game by making the Proof of Burn apply to both active and inactive validators. This approach not only helps provide critical network funding, it also incentivizes validators to participate in consensus in order to earn rewards and avoid the clawback of their previously earned coins. We expect this change to be controversial with some people and we have suspended the implementation of the Proof of Burn on inactive validators for 10 epochs. During that time, people can learn more about it and discuss. If there are substantial objections, the issue will be debated and revisited.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The changes to the validator onboarding and economics may not be guaranteed to reach the desired state, but directionally, they move us closer to the goal: Engaged validators who are stewards of the chain. Implementation of new types of economic incentives and games (for example, delegation) could build on these changes, make the economics more interesting for Carpe miners, and also help disincentivize inattentive validators.&nbsp;</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="next-steps"><strong>Next Steps</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/spring-forward%C2%A0#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to next-steps" title="Direct link to next-steps">​</a></h2>
<p>At present, the network is in Recovery Mode and Carpe miners are able to start the app and check balances and have minimal interactions, but not mine their Tower. Recovery Mode suspends all economic activity to allow for testing and network stabilization. (This also disincentivized actors from front-running or otherwise taking advantage of skewed economics from network halts.) To be clear, while the network is in Recovery Mode no rewards are being paid to anyone – not even validators. One Saturday, 30 April, the network will open again for Carpe miners and we invite everyone to come back in.</p>
<p>Also, as noted above, the Proof of Burn on inactive validators is being held in abeyance until Epoch 185. During that time, if there are objections to this approach, they need to be discussed in the community to determine whether action should be taken.&nbsp;</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="in-conclusion"><strong>In Conclusion</strong><a href="https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/spring-forward%C2%A0#in-conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to in-conclusion" title="Direct link to in-conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Blockchain are infinite games. The game itself evolves and adapts. Passivity and paralysis are not an option.</p>
<p><strong>The 0L network is live and running, as is our global community working towards the mission of a transparent, participatory, liberating, open blockchain network for all. We have dealt with the challenges of the moment to create a stronger foundation for the future, and we will continue to evolve the technology, social contracts, and norms of the project to best accomplish such a mission. Your voice is heard. There are more rewards for Carpe miners, as well as a hard commitment for 50% of the funds to flow to community-building wallets that reward participants that build along with us.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Carpe diem ✊☀️</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>news</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Carpe Goes Multilingual]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/carpe-goes-multilingual</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/carpe-goes-multilingual</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We've released, today, a new version of the 0L Network's Carpe Wallet \& Desktop Miner. This release (v.0\.3\.0\) is our latest release in the Carpe Beta series and includes significant new functionality, including multilingual support and a new tab "Events", which displays a list of events associated with your account (i.e., when coins move in and out of the wallet). This latest version ships with Chinese, Portuguese, and French language support. It is our plan to add additional languages in the near future.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We've released, today, a new version of the 0L Network's Carpe Wallet &amp; Desktop Miner. This release (v.0.3.0) is our latest release in the Carpe Beta series and includes significant new functionality, including multilingual support and a new tab "Events", which displays a list of events associated with your account (i.e., when coins move in and out of the wallet). This latest version ships with Chinese, Portuguese, and French language support. It is our plan to add additional languages in the near future.</p>
<p>To upgrade to the latest version, simply shut down and then restart your Carpe instance. You should be prompted to install the new version. Thanks to all on the Dev Team for making this happen! For those of you who are new to Carpe, <a href="https://github.com/0LNetworkCommunity/carpe" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">follow this link to grab the installer</a> for Mac or WIN</p>
<p>To learn more about Carpe, visit the dedicated page on this site: <a href="http://openlibra.blog/technology/carpe-desktop-app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://openlibra.blog/technology/carpe-desktop-app/</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>carpe</category>
            <category>wallet</category>
            <category>software</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Research Report: Decentralizing Permissioned Blockchain with Delay Towers]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/research-report-decentralizing-permissioned-blockchain-with-delay-towers</link>
            <guid>https://docs.openlibra.io/blog/research-report-decentralizing-permissioned-blockchain-with-delay-towers</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[This report, published 18 March 2022, looks at the Delay Towers mechanism that was pioneered and deployed in the 0L Network.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This report, published 18 March 2022, looks at the Delay Towers mechanism that was pioneered and deployed in the 0L Network.</p>
<p>The article was co-authored by Shashank Motepalli and Hans-Arno Jocobsen of the University of Toronto. We quote the original synopsis below:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Growing excitement around permissionless blockchains is uncovering its latent scalability concerns. Permissioned blockchains offer high transactional throughput and low latencies while compromising decentralization. In the quest for a decentralized, scalable blockchain fabric, i.e., to offer the scalability of permissioned blockchain in a permissionless setting, we present L4L to encourage decentralization over the permissioned Libra network without compromising its sustainability. L4L employs delay towers, -- puzzle towers that leverage verifiable delay functions -- for establishing identity in a permissionless setting. Delay towers cannot be parallelized due to their sequential execution, making them an eco-friendly alternative. We also discuss methodologies to replace validators participating in consensus to promote compliant behavior. Our evaluations found that the cost of enabling decentralization over permissioned networks is almost negligible. Furthermore, delay towers offer an alternative to existing permissionless consensus mechanisms without requiring airdrops or pre-sale of tokens.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>&gt;&gt; <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.09714" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">View the original article, with download link to full report</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>research report</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>